부산은 한반도 남동쪽 해안가에 자리한 해안 도시입니다.
De stad Busan ligt aan de zuidoostelijke kust van het Koreaanse schiereiland,
Byen Busan ligger på Koreahalvøyas sør-østlige kystlinje,
Byen Busan befinder sig på den sydøstlige kystlinje på den koreanske halvø,
Die Stadt Busan liegt an der Südostküste der Koreanischen Halbinsel. Sie ist nur
Thành phố Busan tọa lạc trên bờ biển phía đông nam Bán đảo Triều Tiên,
Staden Pusan ligger vid Koreahalvöns södra kust,
La ciudad de Busan está en la costa sureste de la península de Corea,
La ciudad de Busan se encuentra en la costa sureste de la península de Corea,
The city of Busan sits on the Korean Peninsula’s south-eastern coastline,
La città di Busan si trova sulla costa sud-orientale della penisola coreana,
Kota Busan berada di garis pantai Tenggara Semenanjung Korea,
プサンは朝鮮半島の南東部にある 美しい海沿いの都市
釜山市位於 朝鮮半島東南岸
釜山市座落於南韓半島上的 東南海岸
ปูซาน ตั้งอยู่บนคาบสมุทรเกาหลี ทางชายฝั่งตะวันออกเฉียงใต้
A cidade de Busan fica no litoral sudeste da península coreana e
La ville de Pusan se trouve sur la côte sud-est de la péninsule coréenne.
La ville de Busan, sur la côte sud-est de la péninsule coréenne, est à une courte
Busanin kaupunki sijaitsee Korean niemimaan kaakkoisrannikolla,
이웃 나라 수도인 베이징이나 도쿄까지는 단거리 비행으로,
een korte vlucht vanuit Aziatische hoofdsteden zoals Peking en Tokio
kun en kort flytur unna asiatiske hovedsteder som Beijing og Tokyo,
kun en kort flyrejse fra asiatiske hovedstader som Beijing og Tokyo
einen kurzen Flug von asiatischen Hauptstädten wie Peking und Tokio und 2,5 Stunden
cách thủ đô các nước châu Á như Bắc Kinh và Tokyo chỉ một chặng bay ngắn
bara en kort flygresa från asiatiska huvudstäder som Beijing och Tokyo,
a solo un corto vuelo de capitales asiáticas, como Beijing y Tokio,
a poca distancia en avión de capitales asiáticas como Pekín y Tokio,
just a short flight from Asian capitals like Beijing and Tokyo,
a poche ore di volo da altre capitali asiatiche come Pechino o Tokyo
penerbangan singkat dari ibu kota Asia seperti Beijing dan Tokyo,
東京や北京など アジア主要都市からのアクセスも良好です
從北京和東京等亞洲國家的首都 飛幾個小時就能抵達
離亞洲多個首府，例如北京和東京 只是很短的航線距離
ใช้เวลาบินไม่นานจากเมืองยักษ์ใหญ่ในเอเชีย เช่น กรุงปักกิ่งและกรุงโตเกียว
a apenas um voo curto das capitais Pequim e Tóquio,
On s’y rend rapidement en avion à partir de Pékin ou de Tokyo
distance de vol de grandes capitales comme Pékin et Tokyo,
lyhyen lentomatkan päässä Aasian pääkaupungeista, kuten Pekingistä ja Tokiosta,
서울에서는 고속 열차로 2시간 30분이면 갈 수 있는 거리에 있죠.
en een ritje van tweeënhalf uur met de hogesnelheidstrein vanuit Seoel.
og to og en halv time med høyhastighetstog fra Seoul.
og en tur på 2,5 time med hurtigtoget til Seoul.
mit dem Hochgeschwindigkeitszug von Seoul entfernt.
và cách Seoul 2,5 giờ đi tàu siêu tốc.
och 2,5 timmars resa med snabbtåg från Seoul.
y a un viaje de dos horas y media en tren bala de Seúl.
y a solo dos horas y media en tren bala de Seúl.
and a two-and-a-half hour bullet train ride from Seoul.
e a solo due ore e mezza da Seoul con un treno ad alta velocità.
dan dua jam setengah naik kereta peluru dari Seoul.
ソウルから高速列車を利用すれば わずか 2 時間半
從首爾搭子彈列車出發，也只要 2.5 小時 的車程
由首爾坐子彈火車來這裡，只需 兩個半小時
และเดินทางด้วยรถไฟหัวกระสุนเพียงสองชั่วโมงครึ่ง จากกรุงโซล
e a 2h30 de trem bala de Seul.
et en 2,5 heures en train superexpress à partir de Séoul.
et à 2 h 30 minutes en train de Séoul.
sekä kahden ja puolen tunnin luotijunamatkan päässä Soulista.
우리나라에서 가장 큰 항구이자 두 번째로 큰 도시인 부산은
De grootste haven en op één na grootste stad
Sør-Koreas største havn og nest største by
Sydkoreas største havn og anden største by
Südkoreas größter Hafen und zweitgrößte Stadt
Cảng biển lớn nhất và cũng là thành phố lớn thứ hai Hàn Quốc
Sydkoreas största hamnstad och nästa största stad
El mayor puerto y la segunda ciudad más grande de Corea del Sur
El principal puerto y segunda ciudad de Corea del Sur
South Korea’s largest port and second-largest city
È la città portuale più grande e la seconda in generale della Corea del Sud
Pelabuhan terbesar dan kota kedua terbesar di Korea Selatan
韓国屈指の貿易港 そして首都に次ぐ第二の都市
釜山是韓國第一大港和第二大城
釜山市是南韓最大的港口城市和第二大城市
ที่นี่ใหญ่เป็นอันดับสอง และเป็นเมืองท่าอันดับหนึ่งของเกาหลีใต้
Maior porto e segunda maior cidade da Coreia do Sul,
Le port majeur et la deuxième ville en taille
Principal port et deuxième ville de Corée du Sud,
Etelä-Korean suurin satama ja toiseksi suurin kaupunki
영남 지역의 들쭉날쭉한 해안선을 따라 펼쳐져 있으며
van Zuid-Korea spreidt zich uit over de rotsachtige kustlijn van de regio Yeongnam
sprer seg langs den taggete kystlinjen til regionen Yeongnam,
breder sig langs den ujævne kystlinje af Yeongnam-regionen
erstreckt sich entlang der felsigen Küste der Region Yeongnam und ist
trải mình dọc theo đường bờ biển mấp mô thuộc Khu vực Yeongnam,
breder ut sig längs Yeongnam-regionens klippiga kustlinje,
se extiende a lo largo de la escarpada costa de la región de Yeongnam,
se extiende a lo largo de la escarpada costa de la región de Yeongnam
spreads out along the jagged coastline of the Yeongnam Region,
e si estende lungo la costa frastagliata della regione di Yeongnam,
membentang sepanjang garis pantai Wilayah Yeongnam,
国内有数のリアス式海岸を誇る ヨンナム地域
沿著嶺南地方鋸齒狀的海岸線 一路延伸
在嶺南地區嶙峋的 海岸線旁伸延
ทอดตัวยาวไปตามชายฝั่ง ของภูมิภาคยองนัม
Busan se estende pela costa da região de Yeongnam e é
de Corée du Sud longent le littoral abrupt de la région de Yeongnam, se découpant
elle s'étend sur la côte accidentée de la région de Yeongnam,
levittäytyy pitkin rosoista Yeongnamin alueen rannikkoa,
산으로 둘러싸인 아늑한 도시입니다.
en verrijst daarachter in een zee van bergen.
og stiger opp som et hav av fjell på den andre siden.
og stiger op i havets horisont som bjerge.
von einer Bergkette umgeben.
vươn ra cả vùng núi phía xa.
och tornar upp sig i ett landskap som är omgivet av berg.
y se eleva en un mar de montañas a lo lejos.
y se eleva sobre un mar de montañas.
and rises into a sea of mountains beyond.
con una catena montuosa che le fa da sfondo.
dan menjulang di antara perbukitan tepi pantai.
山々が連なる景色がどこまでも続き
與內陸的群山相連
順著地勢上升到遠處群山之中
ประกอบด้วยภูเขาจำนวนมาก
cercada por montanhas.
sur une mer de montagnes au loin.
à flanc de montagne.
ja sitä ympäröivät lukuisat vuoret.
구석기 시대 사람들을 바위투성이 해안가로 몰려들게 한 조개류부터
Van de schaaldieren die verzamelaars in de oude steentijd naar de woeste kust lokte
Fra skalldyrene som trakk de paleoittiske samlerne til den taggete kysten,
Lige fra skaldyr, som lokkede samlere fra den tidlige stenalder til,
Von den Meeresfrüchten, die altsteinzeitliche Sammler an die Felsenküsten lockten,
Từ bao loài sò ốc đã đưa chân người hái lượm thời Đồ đá Cũ tới bờ biển trắc trở
Från skaldjur – som lockade samlare till dessa steniga stränder under stenåldern –
Desde los mariscos que atrajeron a recolectores paleolíticos a sus litorales escabrosos,
Desde el marisco que atrajo a los recolectores paleolíticos a sus abruptas costas
From the shellfish which drew Paleolithic gatherers to its rugged shores,
Dai molluschi che hanno attirato gli uomini del Paleolitico sulle sue coste irregolari
Dari kerang yang menarik pengumpul Paleolitik ke pantai kasarnya,
旧石器時代の人々も好んで食した 海産物がこの入り江に集まります
從舊石器時代開始，就吸引先民 前來撿拾貝類的嶙峋海岸
舊石器時代人類已經來 這處崎嶇的海岸捕獲貝類食物
ที่นี่มีตั้งแต่กุ้ง หอย ปู ปลา ที่ดึงดูด มนุษย์ยุคหินเก่าให้มาตั้งรกรากที่ชายฝั่งแห่งนี้
Seja pelos moluscos que atraíam coletores no Paleolítico para as margens acidentadas,
Tout à Pusan est lié à l’océan : des chasseurs-cueilleurs paléolithiques
Des coquillages qui ont nourri les hommes au Paléolithique
Ihmiset saapuivat alueelle paleoliittisella kaudella keräämään mereneläviä,
싱싱한 해산물 천국인 자갈치 시장과
tot de eindeloze aanbiedingen op de Jagalchi Fish Market …
til det uendelige utvalget på Jagalchi fiskemarked ...
til de uendelige tilbud på Jagalchis fiskemarked...
bis hin zum reichhaltigen Angebot des Jagalchi-Fischmarkts,
đến bạt ngàn hàng hóa của Chợ Cá Jagalchi,
till Jagalchis fiskmarknad med ett utbud som aldrig sinar,
hasta las interminables opciones del mercado de pescado de Jagalchi,
hasta la casi interminable oferta de la lonja de pescado de Jagalchi,
to the never-ending offerings of Jagalchi Fish Market,
fino all’offerta infinita del mercato del pesce di Jagalchi...
hingga ke Pasar Ikan Jagalchi yang memiliki penawaran tak terbatas,
チャガルチ市場は尽きることがない 自然の恵みあふれる魚市場
到札嘎其魚市場源源不絕的 豐富漁貨
札嘎其魚市場更提供源源不絕 的海產
จนถึงตลาดปลาจากัลชี ที่ไม่เคยหลับใหล
pela variedade encontrada no mercado Jagalchi,
attirés sur la côte par la manne de crustacés aux offres sans fin
à l'immense marché aux poissons de Jagalchi,
joita on yhä saatavilla runsain mitoin Jagalchin kalamarkkinoilla.
옛 조선 시대 선박부터
Van de oude Joseonschepen
Og med de gamle Joseon-skipene
Fra de gamle skibe fra Joseon-dynastien,
von den alten Schiffen des Königreichs Joseon
…từ những con tàu cũ xưa thời Triều Tiên
...från Joseons urgamla fartyg
desde los barcos antiguos de Joseon,
así como desde la antigua flota de la dinastía Joseon
…from the Joseon ships of old,
...o dalle vecchie navi della dinastia Joseon
…dari kapal kuno Joseon,
一方で プサンは朝鮮時代から
…從朝鮮王朝的古老船隻
由古老時代的朝鮮船隻
ตั้งแต่เรือโบราณจากสมัยโชซอน
pelos antigos navios Joseon
du marché aux poissons de Jagalchi
…des vieux gréements de Joseon
Joseon-dynastian vanhat laivat
대한민국 경제 부흥의 주역인 조선소까지
tot de scheepswerven die het Zuid-Koreaanse economische wonder hebben aangedreven,
og verftene som bidrog til Sør-Koreas enorme økonomiske vekst,
til skibsværfterne, som succesfuldt drev den sydkoreanske økonomi...
bis hin zum Hafen, der maßgeblich zu Südkoreas Wirtschaftswunder beitrug,
đến các bến tàu đã góp phần giúp kinh tế Hàn Quốc viết nên kỳ tích,
till skeppsvarven som hjälpte Sydkoreas ekonomi att blomstra;
hasta los astilleros que ayudaron a impulsar el milagro económico de Corea del Sur,
hasta los astilleros que impulsaron el milagro económico nacional,
to the dockyards which helped drive South Korea’s economic miracle,
fino ai cantieri navali che hanno sostenuto il miracolo economico della Corea del Sud,
hingga galangan kapal yang membantu mendorong keajaiban ekonomi Korea Selatan,
造船拠点として 韓国経済をけん引しました
到推動南韓經貿榮景的 現代化船塢
到現在帶動南韓經濟奇蹟 的船塢
จนถึงท่าเรือสำคัญที่ขับเคลื่อน เศรษฐกิจอันรุ่งเรืองของเกาหลีใต้
ou pelos estaleiros que impulsionaram o milagre econômico da Coreia do Sul,
et des navires de la période Joseon aux chantiers maritimes,
aux docks, essentiels dans la réalisation du miracle économique coréen,
ja Etelä-Korean talousihmettä edistäneet lukuisat laivatelakat
부산은 언제나 바다와 함께해 왔죠.
Busan is voor altijd met de oceaan verbonden.
har Busan alltid vært tett knyttet til havet.
Busan har i sandhed altid været forbundet med havet.
war Busan schon immer untrennbar mit dem Meer verbunden.
Busan trọn kiếp gắn bó với đại dương.
Pusan har alltid varit förknippat med havet.
Busan siempre ha estado ligada al mar.
Busan siempre ha estado muy vinculada al mar.
Busan has forever been linked to the ocean.
Busan da sempre è associata al mare.
Busan selamanya dikaitkan dengan laut.
まさに海なくしてプサンの発展はなかったのです
釜山與海洋的關係一向密不可分
釜山與海洋的關係一直密切
เห็นชัดว่าปูซานผูกพันกับมหาสมุทรแบบตัดกันไม่ขาด
Busan sempre esteve ligada ao oceano.
moteurs du miracle économique sud-coréen.
l'histoire de Busan est liée à l'océan.
muistuttavat Busanin yhteydestä mereen.
21세기에 접어들어서도
Terwijl de wereld door de 21e eeuw stoomt,
Og mens verden raser videre inn i det 21. århundre,
I en verden, der fortsat lever videre i det 21. århundrede med hastige skridt,
Auch im 21. Jahrhundert entwickelt sich
Khi cả thế giới mải miết chạy đua cùng thế kỷ 21,
I takt med att civilisationen skrider längre in i 2000-talet,
A medida que el mundo se adentra más en el siglo XXI,
Mientras el mundo se adentra en el siglo XXI,
As the world races further into the 21st century,
Mentre il mondo continua la sua corsa nel 21° secolo,
Ketika dunia berkembang semakin jauh memasuki abad ke-21,
世界が熾烈な競争社会へと変わるなか
隨著全球邁入 21 世紀
當世界趕著要向 21 世紀繼續進發時
ในขณะที่โลกกำลังก้าวสู่ศตวรรษที่ 21
E agora, no século 21,
Pendant que la planète se rue vers l’avenir,
À mesure que le XXIe siècle avance dans sa course,
2000-luvun vuosien vaihtuessa
부산은 계속해서 성장을 거듭하였고
blijft Busan zich ontwikkelen
utvikler Busan seg videre
fortsætter Busan med at udvikle sig
Busan stetig weiter und ist heute ein Ort,
Busan vẫn vững bước trên con đường riêng,
fortsätter Pusan att utvecklas till
Busan sigue evolucionando
Busan no deja de evolucionar
Busan continues to evolve,
Busan non smette di trasformarsi
Busan terus berkembang,
プサンはさらに発展を続けます
釜山也持續成長
釜山繼續蛻變
ปูซานเองก็มีพัฒนาการเช่นกัน
Busan está se tornando um
Pusan évolue dans son coin de paradis,
Busan continue à évoluer
Busan kehittyy edelleen.
이제는 사람들이 열심히 일한 후 꿀 같은 휴식을 즐기면서
tot een havenstad waar hardwerkende Koreanen kunnen ontspannen,
til å bli et sted hvor hardtarbeidende koreanere kan slå ut håret,
og er blevet et fristed for hårdtarbejdende koreanere, som her kan slå håret ud
an dem die Koreaner die Früchte ihrer harten Arbeit ernten,
trở thành thiên đường cho những người con cần mẫn xứ kim chi được sống vô tư lự,
en fristad där hårt arbetande koreaner kan koppla av,
para convertirse en un paraíso donde los coreanos trabajadores pueden relajarse,
hacia un enclave en el que sus residentes pueden relajarse,
into a haven where hard-working Koreans can let their hair down,
in un'isola felice dove gli infaticabili lavoratori coreani possono riposarsi,
menjadi tempat singgah di mana orang Korea pekerja keras dapat bersantai,
癒やしを求める人々が ゆっくりと深呼吸し
並發展成一片樂土，讓辛勤工作的韓國人 在這裡盡情放鬆
成為勤奮的韓國人 可鬆弛下來的天堂
ที่นี่คือเมืองสุดฮิตสำหรับชาวเกาหลีใต้ ที่อยากมาพักผ่อนหย่อนใจ
refúgio para os trabalhadores coreanos que querem relaxar,
où les travailleurs coréens affairés peuvent relaxer,
vers un havre où les coréens peuvent se détendre,
Se on kaupunki, jossa ahkerat korealaiset voivat hengähtää,
과거를 돌아보고
op het verleden kunnen reflecteren
reflektere over fortiden
og mindes fortiden,
sich auf ihre Vergangenheit besinnen
trân trọng quá khứ,
reflektera över det förgångna
reflexionar sobre el pasado,
reflexionar sobre el pasado
reflect on the past,
riflettere sul passato
merenungkan masa lalu,
時に過去に思いをはせ
重溫傳統
一邊懷緬過去
เรียนรู้ประวัติศาสตร์
refletir sobre o passado
méditer sur le passé
muistella mennyttä
미래를 생각하는 안식처가 되었습니다.
en een blik in de toekomst kunnen werpen.
og se inn i fremtiden.
mens de kigger ud mod fremtiden.
und in die Zukunft schauen können.
ngóng chờ tương lai.
och blicka in i framtiden.
y mirar hacia el futuro.
y escudriñar el futuro.
and peer into the future.
e dare una sbirciata al futuro.
dan berlayar ke masa depan.
そして未来の気配を感じる街
並放眼未來
一邊展望將來
และเตรียมพร้อมสู่โลกอนาคต
e planejar o futuro.
et se tourner vers le futur.
et se pencher vers l'avenir.
ja tähyillä tulevaisuuteen.
북적이는 항구에서는 부산의 활발한 경제 활동을 뒷받침하고
Hoewel het de bruisende haven is die de economische welvaart van Busan aandrijft,
Mens den livlige havnen er fundamentet for Busans økonomiske livskraft,
Skønt det travle havneområde er livskraften bag Busans økonomi,
Obwohl der Hafen Busans zum wirtschaftlichen Erfolg beiträgt,
Chẳng chịu kém bến cảng sầm uất đặt nền móng cho tiềm lực kinh tế của Busan,
Samtidigt som denna livliga hamnstad är en grundpelare för landets ekonomi,
Mientras que el bullicioso puerto es la base de la vitalidad económica de Busan,
Aunque su concurrido puerto sustenta la vitalidad económica de la ciudad,
While the bustling port underpins Busan’s economic vitality,
Anche se è il trafficato porto di Busan a sostenere la sua economia,
Meskipun pelabuhan sibuk yang menyokong kekuatan ekonomi Busan,
海運がプサンの 発展のカギであることには変わりなくても
熙來攘往的港口是釜山 的經濟命脈
繁忙的海港支撐著釜山 的經濟活力
แม้ว่าท่าเรือของปูซานจะเป็นกำลังหลัก เสริมความแกร่งของเศรษฐกิจละแวกนี้
O porto de Busan é o principal responsável pela economia da cidade
La ville doit sa vitalité économique à son port animé,
Si le port est le moteur de l'activité économique de Busan,
Vaikka kuhiseva satama onkin Busanin talouden perusta,
도시의 해변가는 아시아 전역에서 찾아온 여행객들의 발길을 사로잡죠.
trekken de stranden van de stad steeds meer reizigers vanuit heel Azië.
er det strendene som i stadig økende grad lokker til seg reisende fra hele Asia.
er det byens strande, som gang på gang tiltrækker rejsende fra hele Asien.
sind es doch die Strände der Stadt, die immer mehr Urlauber aus ganz Asien anziehen.
những bãi biển trong thành phố ngày càng thu hút du khách từ khắp châu Á.
är det Pusans stränder som lockar allt fler resenärer hit från hela Asien.
son las playas de la ciudad las que atraen a cada vez más viajeros de toda Asia.
son sus playas las que, cada vez más, atraen a viajeros de toda Asia.
it’s the city’s beaches which increasingly draw travellers from all over Asia.
sono le spiagge della città ad attirare sempre più turisti provenienti da tutta l’Asia.
namun pantai kota inilah yang memikat semakin banyak traveler dari seluruh Asia.
この地のビーチに魅力を感じて訪れる 旅行者を受け入れてくれる懐の大きさも特徴です
不過，這裡的海灘才是吸引全亞洲旅客 趨之若鶩的魅力所在
但吸引越來越多亞洲旅客前來 的卻是釜山美麗的海灘
แต่ชายหาดของเมืองต่างหาก ที่ดึงดูดให้นักท่องเที่ยวทั่วเอเชียเดินทางมาเยือน
e as praias atraem cada vez mais viajantes de toda a Ásia.
mais ce sont ses plages qui attirent de plus en plus les touristes asiatiques.
ce sont ses plages qui attirent les voyageurs venus de toute l'Asie.
kaupungin rannat houkuttelevat joka vuosi lisää matkailijoita kaikkialta Aasiasta.
부산역에서 지하철로 40분 정도만 이동하면 주요 명소인 해운대를 만나실 수 있는데요.
Slechts een metrorit van 40 minuten vanaf Station Busan ligt de beroemdste attractie van de stad:
40 minutter med t-bane fra Busan stasjon ligger byens hovedattraksjon,
Du finder byens mest populære seværdighed, Haeundae Strand, kun 40 minutter med metroen fra Busan Station,
Nur 40 Minuten mit der U-Bahn vom Bahnhof Busan entfernt ist die Hauptattraktion:
Và nổi bật nhất trong số ấy, chỉ mất 40 phút đi tàu điện ngầm từ Ga Busan,
Bara en 40 minuters resa med tunnelbana från Pusan station ligger stadens populäraste sevärdhet,
A solo 40 minutos en metro de la estación de Busan se encuentra la atracción principal de la ciudad,
A solo 40 minutos en metro de la estación de Busan se encuentra su atracción estrella,
Just a 40-minute subway ride from Busan Station is the city’s star attraction,
A solo 40 minuti di autobus dalla stazione di Busan si trova la sua attrazione principale,
Hanya 40 menit naik kereta bawah tanah dari Stasiun Busan terdapat objek wisata terpopuler kota ini,
プサン駅から地下鉄を利用して 40 分で 人気スポットが目の前に
從釜山車站搭地鐵只要 40 分鐘 就會來到這裡的明星景點
由釜山站坐 40 分鐘地鐵 便可抵達釜山市星級景點—
นั่งรถไฟใต้ดินจากสถานีปูซานมาเพียง 40 นาที ก็จะพบสถานที่ท่องเที่ยวสำคัญ
A apenas 40 minutos de metrô da estação Busan fica a maior atração da cidade:
Haeundae, à 40 minutes en métro de la station Pusan, est la plage-vedette de la ville
À 40 minutes en métro de la gare de Busan se trouve l'attraction phare de la ville,
40 minuutin metromatkan päässä Busanin asemalta sijaitsee alueen tunnetuin nähtävyys,
이곳은 한국에서 가장 넓은 해변이자 가장 인기 많은 관광 명소예요.
het strand Haeundae, de grootste en populairste badplaats van Zuid-Korea.
Haeundae strand – Sør-Koreas største og mest populære strand.
som er Sydkoreas største og mest eftertragtede tilholdssted.
der Strand von Haeundae, Südkoreas größter und beliebtester Strand.
là Bãi biển Haeundae không những lớn nhất mà còn được yêu thích nhất Hàn Quốc.
Haeundae Beach – Sydkoreas största och mest omtyckta badstrand.
la playa Haeundae, el lugar junto a la playa más grande y más amado de Corea del Sur.
la playa de Haeundae, la zona costera más grande y apreciada de Corea del Sur.
Haeundae Beach, South Korea’s biggest and best-loved beachside hangout.
la spiaggia di Haeundae, la più grande della Corea e uno dei punti di ritrovo balneari più amati.
Pantai Haeundae, tepi patai tempat bergaul terbesar dan terfavorit di Korea Selatan.
海雲台は 愛してやまない憩いの場
海雲臺海水浴場，也是韓國規模最大 且最受歡迎的濱海休閒勝地
海雲台海水浴場，它是南韓最大 和最高人氣的海傍聚腳點
ชายหาดแฮอึนแด หาดที่ใหญ่ที่สุด และเป็นที่นิยมที่สุดในประเทศ
Praia de Haeundae, a maior e mais popular da Coreia do Sul.
et le lieu de rencontre maritime le plus grand et le plus prisé de Corée du Sud.
Haeundae Beach, la plage la plus grande et la plus prisée du pays.
Haeundaen ranta, joka on Etelä-Korean suurin ja suosituin hiekkaranta.
길게 펼쳐진 모래사장을 따라 동쪽으로 가면 달맞이 고개가 나옵니다.
Volg de lange zandstrook richting het oosten, naar de Dalmaji-heuvel,
Følg de lange sandstrekkene østover til Dalmaji-åsen,
Gå langs stranden mod øst til Dalmaji Bakke,
Östlich des langen Sandstrands liegt die Anhöhe Dalmaji Hill, deren
Phía đông dải cát dài, Đồi Dalmaji
Följ de långa sanddynerna österut mot Dalmaji Hill,
Sigue la gran extensión de arena hacia el este hasta llegar a la colina Dalmaji,
Recorre el extenso tramo de arena hacia al este hasta la colina de Dalmaji,
Follow the long sweep of sands eastward to Dalmaji Hill,
Dirigendovi verso est, seguite la lunga striscia di sabbia fino alla collina Dalmaji,
Ikuti bentangan panjang pasing pantai ke arah timur ke Bukit Dalmaji,
海岸沿いを東に進めば そこはタルマジ ヒル
沿著連綿不絕的沙灘往東走，就會來到 迎月之丘
沿著長長的沙灘向東走 便可來到迎月之丘
เดินตามหาดทรายสวยๆ ไปทางตะวันออก คือเทือกเขาดัลมาจิ
Siga a longa faixa de areia na direção do Monte Dalmaji,
Dirigez-vous vers l’est jusqu’à la colline de Dalmaji,
Cette longue bande de sable s'étend à l'est vers la colline de Dalmaji,
Seuraa yli kilometrin pituista hiekkarantaa itään Dalmaji-mäelle,
옛날에는 시인들의 감수성을 자극하고 오늘날에는 커피 마니아들의
een uitkijkpunt geprezen door de rondtrekkende dichters van vroeger
et utkikkspunkt som har blitt nytt av vandrende poeter i fortiden,
et smukt landskab elsket af fortidens omstrejfende poeter
Panoramablick seit jeher Dichter und Wanderer anzog –
làm say lòng những thi sĩ phiêu lãng thuở xưa
en utsiktsplats älskad av gårdagens poeter och
un mirador adorado por los poetas errantes de antaño
un mirador muy apreciado por los poetas errantes de antaño
an outlook adored by the wandering poets of yesteryear
un punto panoramico molto amato dai poeti itineranti di ieri
pemadangan yang dipuja oleh penyair yang mengembara di masa lalu
かつて放浪詩人が その美しさをたたえた場所
這裡過去是詩人吟詩歌詠 的所在
深愛這處景致的包括昔日的 流浪詩人
สถานที่ชมวิวอันงดงามสำหรับนักกวี ในอดีต
uma paisagem adorada pelos poetas do passado
le point de vue préféré des poètes d’autrefois
prisée des poètes vagabonds d'autrefois
jonka näköaloja ovat ihastelleet niin entisaikojen runoilijat
사랑을 듬뿍 받는 곳이에요.
en de koffieliefhebbers van nu.
og som beundres av kaffeelskere i dag.
og nutidens kaffeentusiaster.
und heute auch Kaffeeliebhaber.
và cả bao người chuộng cà phê ngày nay.
nutidens kaffe-entusiaster.
y los amantes del café de ahora.
y los amantes del café de hoy en día.
and the coffee lovers of today.
e dagli amanti del caffè di oggi.
dan pecinta kopi masa kini.
今ではコーヒーの名所
現在則是咖啡愛好者鍾愛的去處
和今日的愛咖啡人士
และสำหรับคอกาแฟในปัจจุบัน
e pelos visitantes do presente.
et des amateurs de café d’aujourd’hui.
et des amateurs de café d'aujourd'hui.
kuin nykypäivän kahvinystävät.
해운대 동쪽 끄트머리에 자리한
Als je aan de oostelijke rand van Haeundae bent,
Når du er på østsiden av Haeundae,
Mens du besøger den østlige del af Haeundae,
Am östlichen Ende von Haeundae schlendert
Cũng ở đầu phía đông Haeundae,
När du är vid Haeundaes östra ände
Del extremo este de Haeundae,
No te vayas del extremo este de Haeundae
While at Haeundae’s eastern end,
Mentre siete all'estremità orientale di Haeundae,
Sementara di ujung timur Haeundae,
海雲台の東端に
來到海雲臺東側
來到海雲台東端
สุดเขตตะวันออกของหาดแฮอึนแด
No extremo leste de Haeundae,
Traversez le parc Dongbaek pour vous rendre
À l'extrémité est de Haeundae,
Kulje Haeundaen itäosassa
동백공원 산책길을 지나면 APEC 하우스를 마주하게 돼요.
volg je de paden door het Dongbaek-park naar het APEC House,
kan du følge veien gjennom Dongbaek park til APEC-huset.
kan du passende kigge forbi Dongbaek Park og APEC Hus,
man durch den Dongbaek-Park zum APEC House,
đường to lối nhỏ vắt ngang Công viên Dongbaek, dẫn đến APEC House,
kan du passa på att ta en promenad genom Dongbaek Park till APEC House,
toma los senderos que atraviesan el parque Dongbaek hasta APEC House,
sin atravesar el parque de Dongbaek hasta la casa APEC,
take the paths through Dongbaek Park to APEC House,
incamminatevi sul percorso che va dal parco Dongbaek alla APEC House,
ikuti jalan setapak melewati Taman Dongbaek ke Gedung APEC,
冬柏公園を抜けると APEC ハウスが見えてきます
不妨穿過冬柏公園，前往 APEC 世峰樓
沿小徑穿過冬柏公園到 APEC 世峰樓
คือสวนดงแบก และที่อยู่ติดกันคือศูนย์ประชุมเอเปก เฮาส์
caminhe do Parque Dongbaek até a APEC House,
sur les lieux du sommet de l’APEC de 2005,
les sentiers de Dongbaek Park mènent à la maison de l'APEC,
Dongbaekin puiston polkuja Nurimaru APEC Houseen,
이곳은 2005년도에 개최된 정상 회의 기간 동안 아태지역 지도자들이
waar leiders uit Azië en het Pacifische gebied van een aantal van de meest gewaardeerde uitzichten van Busan genoten
Her kunne ledere fra Asia og Stillehavet nyte noen av Busans flotteste utsikter
hvor asiatiske ledere nød godt af Busans mest eftertragtede udsigter
wo 2005 die Asiatisch-Pazifische Wirtschaftsgemeinschaft zusammentraf, um
nơi các nhà lãnh đạo châu Á và Thái Bình Dương thưởng lãm những cảnh sắc nổi danh nhất Busan
där politiska ledare från Asien och Stillahavsområdet beundrade några av Pusans favoritvyer
donde los líderes de Asia y el Pacífico disfrutaron de algunas de las mejores vistas de Busan
donde los líderes asiáticos y del Pacífico disfrutaron de las mejores vistas de Busan
where Asian and Pacific leaders enjoyed some of Busan’s most celebrated views
dove i leader asiatici e del Pacifico hanno ammirato alcuni dei panorami più celebri di Busan,
di mana pemimpin negara Asia dan Pasifik menikmati pemandangan Busan yang paling memesona
2005 年 APEC 首脳が プサンの絶景を
這裡是 2005 年亞太經合會期間 亞太地區的領袖齊聚一堂
當年亞太經合領袖出席 2005 年峰會 便在這裡欣賞釜山
สถานที่ที่ผู้นำในแถบเอเชียแปซิฟิก ได้เดินทางมาพบปะและชมวิวอันน่าประทับใจ
construída especialmente para o encontro de líderes da Ásia e do Pacífico
où les dirigeants présents ont pu profiter des panoramas les plus renommés
qui a accueilli dans un cadre magnifique les leaders politiques de l'Asie et du Pacifique
jossa Aasian ja Tyynenmeren johtavat ihailivat Busanin kauneimpia maisemia
부산의 수려한 경치를 조망했던 장소입니다.
tijdens hun conferentie in 2005.
under konferansen i 2005.
under topmødet i 2005.
vor beeindruckender Kulisse zu tagen.
trong hội nghị thượng đỉnh năm 2005.
under toppmötet 2005.
durante su cumbre en 2005.
durante la cumbre de 2005.
during their 2005 summit.
durante il summit del 2005.
selama pertemuan mereka pada tahun 2005.
ここで楽しみました
欣賞釜山絕色美景的所在地
最著名的風景
ในการประชุมปี 2005
em 2005.
de Pusan.
lors d'un sommet en 2005.
vuoden 2005 APEC-kokouksen aikana.
언제나 색다른 매력을 풍기는 부산의 바다는
De altijd veranderende kustlijn van Busan biedt
Busans varierte kystlinje har landskap
Busans forunderlige kystlinje byder på smukke landskaber
Die vielfältigen Küstenabschnitte von Busan bieten
Đường bờ biển đa dạng mà tấp nập trò vui của Busan
Pusans variationsrika kust erbjuder natur
La siempre cambiante costa de Busan ofrece paisajes
La siempre cambiante costa de Busan
Busan’s ever-changing coastline offers scenery
La costa di Busan, in continuo mutamento,
Pantai Busan yang selalu berubah-ubah menawarkan pemandangan
折々の変化を見せるプサンの海で
釜山的海岸線風情萬種
釜山海岸線的風景變幻多端
นอกจากความสวยงามแล้ว ชายฝั่งของปูซาน
O litoral sempre em transformação de Busan
Le littoral toujours changeant de Pusan
Le littoral de Busan offre des paysages
Busanin muuttuvalta rannikolta löytyy maisemia
취향에 맞는 다양한 액티비티를 즐기거나 경치를 감상할 수 있어요.
een landschap en activiteiten voor elk humeur.
og aktiviteter for alle humør.
og oplevelser til ethvert humør.
Aussichten und Aktivitäten für jeden Geschmack.
là thiên đường cho tất cả.
och aktiviteter som passar alla.
y actividades para todos los estados de ánimo.
cuenta con paisajes y actividades para todos los gustos.
and activities to match your every mood.
offre panorami e attività che soddisferanno ogni capriccio.
dan aktivitas yang sesuai dengan suasana hati Anda.
景色やレジャーを堪能
您可以配合心情，選擇喜愛的景致或活動
亦有不同的當地活動，配合自己的心情
ยังมีกิจกรรมมากมายที่รองรับนักท่องเที่ยวทุกประเภท
tem paisagens e atividades para todos os gostos.
offre un paysage et des activités
et des activités infiniment variés.
ja tekemistä moneen eri lähtöön.
반달 모양의
Voor volledige ontspanning
For maksimal avslapning
Trænger du til ren afslapning,
Um auszuspannen,
Giây phút thư thái nhất
Om du är ute efter total avslappning
Para una relajación total,
Si buscas relajarte,
For total relaxation,
Per immergervi nel relax più totale,
Untuk relaksasi total,
ただゆっくりと
想徹底放鬆的話
想要完全地鬆弛嗎？
ทั้งการนั่งพักผ่อน
Para relaxar,
qui conviendront à tous vos états d’âme.
Pour une détente absolue,
Jos haluat rentoutua,
광안리 해수욕장에서 타월 한 장을 깔고 느긋하게 휴식을 취해 보세요.
leg je je handdoek op het halvemaanvormige strand Gwangalli
kan du brette ut håndkleet på den halvmåneformede Gwangalli strand
kan du folde dit håndklæde ud på Gwangalli Strand
können Sie Ihr Handtuch am halbmondförmigen Strand von Gwangalli ausrollen
là khi ta nhẹ trải chiếc khăn mềm trên Bãi biển Gwangalli hình bán nguyệt,
kan du rulla ut badhandduken på den halvmåneformade Gwangalli Beach.
acomoda tu toalla en la curva de media luna de playa Gwangalli,
extiende tu toalla sobre la media luna de la playa de Gwangalli
unroll your towel on the half-moon curve of Gwangalli Beach,
srotolate il telo da mare lungo la curva a mezzaluna della spiaggia Gwangalli
berjemurlah di pantai yang melengkung berbentuk bulan setengah Pantai Gwangalli,
タオルを砂浜に広げ 広安里ビーチの
前往廣安里海水浴場的半月型海灘 鋪開浴巾
在廣安里海水浴場的半月型沙灘上攤開 您的沙灘巾
ปูเสื่อปิกนิกบนหาดรูปพระจันทร์ครึ่งดวง ที่หาดควางอัลลี
estenda sua toalha nas areias da Praia de Gwangalli
Pour relaxer pleinement, déroulez votre serviette sur la demi-lune ensablée
rien de tel que de s'étendre sur la plage en demi-lune de Gwangalli Beach,
voit loikoilla auringossa puolikuun muotoisella Gwangallin rannalla.
부드러운 파도와
en geniet je van het kalme water,
og nyte det behagelige vannet,
og nyde bølgernes brusen,
und das ruhige Meer,
ngụp lặn giữa nước mát dịu êm,
Här får du njuta av lugna vatten,
y disfruta el agua tranquila,
y disfruta de sus serenas aguas,
and enjoy gentle waters,
e godetevi le sue acque calme,
dan nikmati air yang lemut,
穏やかな海で
就能享受和緩的柔浪
享受輕柔的海水
ชมคลื่นทะเลแสนสงบ
e aproveite as águas tranquilas,
de la plage Gwangalli et profitez
avec ses eaux paisibles,
Nauti lempeistä laineista,
여유로운 분위기,
de ontspannen sfeer
den rolige stemningen
den afslappede atmosfære
die relaxte Stimmung und die
đắm chìm trong nhịp đời thư thái
en avkopplande atmosfär och utsikten över
el ambiente relajado
su ambiente tranquilo
laid-back vibes,
la sua atmosfera rilassata
suasana santai,
安らぎの空間と
悠閒的氛圍
輕鬆的氛圍
ในบรรยากาศชิลๆ
o clima de sossego
des eaux calmes, de l’ambiance désinvolte
son atmosphère calme
rennosta tunnelmasta
광안대교의 근사한 모습이 인상적일 거예요.
en het uitzicht op de Gwangan-brug.
og utsikten til broen Gwangandaegyo.
og udsigten til Diamond Bro.
Aussicht auf die Diamond Bridge genießen.
và thảnh thơi ngắm Cầu Diamond.
Diamond Bridge.
y las vistas del puente Gwangan.
y sus vistas del puente de Diamante.
and views to Diamond Bridge.
e la vista sul ponte Diamond.
dan pemandangan ke arah Diamond Bridge.
ダイアモンド ブリッジの眺めを満喫
和鑽石橋的美麗景致
和廣安大橋的景致
และชมวิวสะพานควางอัน
e vista da Diamond Bridge.
et de la vue sur le pont Diamond.
et ses vues sur le pont de Diamant.
ja näkymistä Gwangandaegyon sillalle.
활동적인 여행을 좋아하신다면
Als je op zoek bent naar avontuur,
Dersom du er ute etter et eventyr,
Er du eventyrlysten,
Abenteuerlustige können im Fischerdorf
Ai muốn trải nghiệm chút phiêu lưu
Om du är på jakt efter äventyr,
Si buscas una aventura,
Si, por el contrario, buscas aventura,
If you’re looking for adventure,
Se siete in cerca di avventura,
Jika Anda mencari petualangan,
冒険心を満たそうと思っているなら
想冒險的話
嚮往探險的話
หากคุณเป็นผู้ที่รักการผจญภัย
Se você gosta de aventura,
En quête d’aventure?
Les plus aventuriers prendront un bateau
Jos kaipaat seikkailuja,
청사포 어촌 마을에서 배를 빌려 낚시를 떠나 보세요.
kun je mee met een charter vanuit het visstadje Cheongsapo.
kan du bli med på en tur i fiskerlandsbyen Cheongsapo.
kan du stige ombord på en fiskekutter i landsbyen Cheongsapo,
Cheongsapo eine Bootsfahrt unternehmen.
chỉ cần đến làng chài Cheongsapo thuê tàu ra khơi,
ta en charterutflykt till Cheongsapos fiskeby
súbete a un barco en el pueblo pesquero de Cheongsapo.
súbete a un barco en la aldea pesquera de Cheongsapo
join a charter at the fishing village of Cheongsapo.
non perdetevi il villaggio di pescatori di Cheongsapo,
bergabunglah dengan kapal sewaan di desa nelayan Cheongsapo.
青沙浦村のチャーター クルーズがおすすめです
可以前往青沙浦的漁村包船出海
到青沙浦漁村登上包租專船
ต้องไปร่วมก๊วนกับหมู่บ้านชาวประมงที่ชองซาโพ
pegue uma lancha na vila de pescadores Cheongsapo
Embarquez sur un bateau de pêche à Cheongsapo
dans le village de pêcheurs de Cheongsapo.
lähde kalastusretkelle Cheongsapon kalastajakylässä.
아니면 용호동 끄트머리에 있는 스카이워크를 걸으며
Of zet een paar stappen op de skywalk aan het einde van het schiereiland Yongho-Dong
Du kan også stige ut på skywalken på enden av halvøya Yongho-Dong
eller du kan gå en tur langs Yongho-Dong-halvøens skywalk
Oder Sie erklimmen den Skywalk am Ende der Halbinsel Yongho-Dong und
mạnh dạn bước trên đường đi bộ trên cao ở cuối Bán đảo Yongho-Dong
eller kliv ut på Oryukdo Skywalk på änden av halvön i Yongho-Dong
O visita el mirador en el extremo de la península de Yongho-Dong
o recorre el paso elevado en el extremo de la península de Yongho-Dong
Or step out onto the skywalk at the end of the Yongho-Dong Peninsula,
oppure passeggiate sulla passerella sopraelevata all’estremità della penisola di Yongho-Dong
Atau berjalan di skywalk di ujung Semenanjung Yongho-Dong,
龍湖洞半島の最先端で スカイ ウォークから
或是踏上龍湖洞半島 末端的天空步道
或到龍湖洞半島盡頭處踏上 天空步道
หรือก้าวขามาเหยียบสกายวอล์ค ที่สุดเขตคาบสมุทรยงโฮดง
ou suba na plataforma na península de Yongho-Dong
ou avancez sur le promontoire au bout de la péninsule Yongho-Dong
À l'extrémité de la péninsule de Yongho-Dong, la promenade aérienne offre
Tai astele lasiselle näköalatasanteelle Yongho-dongin niemen päässä
부산 앞바다의 오륙도가 선사하는 멋진 경치를 감상해 보세요.
en neem het uitzicht op de Oryukdo-eilanden net van de kust in je op.
og betrakte utsikten over Oryukdo-øyene like utenfor kysten.
og nyde udsigten fra Oryukdo-øerne ud for kysten.
genießen den Blick auf die Inselgruppe Oryukdo direkt vor der Küste.
và mê đắm bức tranh Đảo Oryukdo ngay ngoài khơi.
och beskåda utsikten över Oryukdo-öarna som ligger precis utanför kusten.
y disfruta las vistas de las islas Oryukdo cerca en la costa.
y admira las vistas de las islas de Oryukdo mar adentro.
and take in the views of the Oryukdo Islands just offshore.
per ammirare al meglio il panorama delle vicine isole Oryukdo.
dan nikmati pemandangan Kepulauan Oryukdo di lepas pantai.
目の前に広がる五六島の景色を 海の上から眺めます
欣賞一水之隔的五六島 的優美景致
飽覽離岸不遠的五六島 明媚風光
ชมวิวสวยๆ ของหมู่เกาะออยุคโด จากนอกชายฝั่ง
para admirar as paisagens das Ilhas Oryukdo.
et observez les îles d’Oryukdo qui se dessinent au large.
des vues époustouflantes sur les îles voisines d'Oryukdo.
ja katsele Oryukdo-saarille avautuvia maisemia.
역사에 대해서도 알아보고 싶으신가요?
Op zoek naar een beetje verlichting?
Klar for å få dypere innsikt?
Har du brug for en lille opmuntring?
Sind Sie auf der Suche nach Erleuchtung?
Tìm ánh sáng cho tâm hồn lạc lối ư?
Söker du ett spirituellt lugn?
¿Buscas iluminación?
¿Buscas un poco de iluminación?
Seeking a little enlightenment?
Cercate un po' di ispirazione mistica?
Mencari pencerahan?
仏の教えに触れるなら
想體驗涅槃的境界嗎？
想尋找心靈啟迪嗎？
ถ้าอยากจะไปสงบจิตสงบใจสักหน่อย
Buscando autoconhecimento?
En quête d’intériorité?
Si vous recherchez la spiritualité,
Kiehtovatko hengelliset kokemukset?
그렇다면 기장으로 향해 보세요.
Ga naar Gijang
Dra til Gijang
Tag til Gijang,
Dann besichtigen Sie Gijang und
Sao không đến huyện Gijang
Bege dig till Gijang
Dirígete a Gijang
Entonces ve a Gijang
Head to Gijang,
Andate a Gijang
Pergilah ke Gijang,
機張へ足を延ばしてみましょう
前往機張郡
您可去到機張
ก็ต้องที่ กีจัง
Vá até Gijang
Rendez-vous à Gijang
vous pourrez vous rendre au temple
Suuntaa Gijangiin
보기 드문 바닷가 사찰인 해동용궁사에서
en doe een wens bij de Haedong Yonggungsa-tempel,
og ønsk deg noe i Haedong Yonggungsa-tempelet,
og ønsk dig noget særligt ved Haedong Yonggungsa Tempel,
bitten Sie im Tempel Haedong Yonggungsa um einen Wunsch.
và tỏ lời ước nguyện tại Chùa Haedong Yonggungsa,
och önska dig något vid Haedong Yonggungsa- templet,
y pide un deseo en el templo Haedong Yonggungsa,
y pide un deseo en el templo de Haedong Yonggungsa,
and make a wish at the Haedong Yonggungsa Temple,
ed esprimete un desiderio nel tempio di Haedong Yonggungsa,
dan berdoa di Kuil Haedong Yonggungsa,
海東龍宮寺で 願い事をしてみましょう
到歷史悠久的海東龍宮寺 許願祈福
的海東龍宮寺 許個願
อย่าลืมแวะไหว้พระขอพรที่วัด แฮดอง ยงกุงซา
e visite o templo Haedong Yonggungsa, um dos poucos templos
et faites un vœu au temple Haedong Yonggungsa,
Haedong Yonggungsa à Gijang,
ja tee toivomus Haedong Yonggungsan temppelissä,
간절하게 소원을 비는 경험을 해 보세요.
een van de weinige Koreaanse boeddhistische tempels die aan zee zijn gebouwd.
et av de få buddhisttemplene i Korea som ligger ved havet.
der er et af de få buddhistiske templer i Korea, som er bygget ved havet.
Er ist einer der wenigen buddhistischen Tempel in Korea, die direkt am Meer erbaut wurden.
một trong những ngôi chùa Phật giáo hiếm hoi tại Hàn Quốc xây bên bờ đại dương.
ett av de få buddhistiska tempel i Korea som byggdes vid havet.
uno de los pocos templos budistas en Corea construido junto al mar.
uno de los pocos templos budistas de Corea construidos junto al mar.
one of the few Buddhist temples in Korea built by the ocean.
uno dei rari templi buddisti coreani a pochi passi dal mare.
salah satu dari sedikit kuil Buddha di Korea yang di bangun di tepi laut.
ここは 海のすぐそばに建立された 仏教寺院
這座寺廟是韓國少數屹立於海畔的 佛寺之一
這座在大海旁邊的佛教廟宇 在韓國較少見
วัดของชาวพุทธไม่กี่แห่งในเกาหลี ที่ตั้งอยู่ริมน้ำ
da Coreia do Sul construídos perto do oceano.
un des rares temples bouddhistes de Corée construits au bord de l’océan.
l'un des quelques temples bouddhistes coréens façonnés par l'océan.
joka on yksi Korean merenrannalle rakennetuista buddhalaistemppeleistä.
오랜 역사를 자랑하는 영도대교를 건너 태종대공원으로 발걸음을 옮겨보세요.
Steek de historische Yeongdodaegyo-brug over en ga naar het Taejongdae-park.
Kryss den historiske Yeongdodaegyo-broen og dra til Taejongdae park.
Kryds den historiske Yeongdodaegyo Bro, og tag et smut forbi Taejongdae Park.
Überqueren Sie die alte Yeongdodaegyo-Klappbrücke, um zum Taejongdae-Park zu gelangen.
Bên kia Cầu Yeongdodaegyo lịch sử, Công viên Taejongdae ấn tượng biết bao.
Korsa den historiska Yeongdodaegyobron och promenera vidare mot Taejongdae Park.
Cruza el histórico puente Yeongdodaegyo y dirígete al parque Taejongdae.
Cruza el histórico puente de Yeongdodaegyo hacia el parque de Taejongdae.
Cross historic Yeongdodaegyo Bridge and head to Taejongdae Park.
Attraversate lo storico ponte Yeongdodaegyo e incamminatevi verso il parco Taejongdae.
Seberangi Jembatan Yeongdodaegyo yang bersejarah dan pergilah ke Taman Taejongdae.
歴史ある影島大橋を渡り 太宗台公園へ
越過歷史悠久的影島大橋，就會來到 對岸的太宗台公園
走過歷史古蹟影島大橋來到 太宗台公園
ข้ามสะพานยองโดแดเกียวอันเก่าแก่ ไปยังสวนแทจงแด
Atravesse a histórica ponte Yeongdodaegyo e vá até o parque Taejongdae.
Traversez le pont historique Yeongdodaegyo et dirigez-vous vers le parc Taejongdae.
Au-delà du pont historique de Yeongdodaegyo, Taejongdae Park abrite
Ylitä historiallinen Yeongdodaegyon silta ja suuntaa Taejongdaen puistoon.
전해 내려오는 전설에 따르면 이 절벽은 신선과 선녀들이 내려와
Volgens de legendes waren het deze kliffen
Legenden sier at det var disse klippene
Det siges, at det var ved disse klipper, guder og gudinder drog til
Der Legende nach kamen die Göttinnen und Götter einst an diese Klippen,
Truyền thuyết kể rằng những vách đá nơi ấy
Det var hit, enligt legenden,
Fue en estos acantilados donde, de acuerdo a la leyenda,
Fue en estos acantilados donde, según la leyenda,
It was at these cliffs where, according to legend,
Secondo la leggenda, su queste scogliere
yang berada di tebing ini di mana, menurut legenda,
伝説によれば 神と女神がこの崖で
根據傳說，這裡的懸崖峭壁 曾經是
相傳這裡的山崖 曾經
ผาแห่งนี้เป็นสถานที่ที่เทพและเทพี ในตำนาน
Segundo a lenda, os deuses e as deusas vinham relaxar
C’est sur ces falaises que, selon la légende, les dieux et
les falaises où, selon la légende,
Vanhan legendan mukaan juuri näillä kalliojyrkänteillä
멋진 경치를 즐기며 노닌 곳이기도 하며
waar goden en godinnen ooit kwamen om te ontspannen
guder og gudinner kom til for å slappe av,
for at slappe af og stedet,
um sich zu entspannen.
từng đón bao thần tiên đến nghỉ chân
som gudar och gudinnor kom för att koppla av,
dioses y diosas vinieron una vez a relajarse
los dioses bajaron a relajarse,
gods and goddesses once came to relax,
le divinità venivano a rilassarsi
dewa dan dewi pernah datang untuk bersantai di sini,
つかの間の休息を楽しみ
無數神祇和女神的歇腳處
是諸神喜歡來此消閒的地方
ใช้เป็นสถานที่พักผ่อน
nessas falésias
les déesses venaient se reposer et que
les dieux et déesses venaient se détendre,
jumalat ja jumalattaret aikoinaan lepäsivät.
29대 신라왕인 태종무열왕이 구름 사이로 화살을 쏘며 사냥을 즐긴 곳이기도 해요.
en waar de 29e koning van Silla in zijn vrije tijd pijlen in voorbij komende wolken schoot.
og hvor den 29. kongen av Silla tilbrakte ferien sin ved å skyte piler på skyene som gled forbi.
hvor den 29. konge af Silla brugte sin tid på at skyde med bue og pile ud i horisonten.
Der 29. König von Silla schoss von hier aus zum Vergnügen Pfeile in die vorbeiziehenden Wolken.
và cả vị vua đời thứ 29 nước Tân La tới lúc thư nhàn, lấy trò bắn tên lên mây trời làm vui.
och även hit som den 29:e kungen av Silla kom på sin fritid för att skjuta iväg pilar mot de förbiseglande molnen.
y el 29º rey de Silla pasó su tiempo libre disparando flechas a las nubes que pasan.
y donde el 29.º rey de Silla disfrutaba disparando flechas a las nubes que pasaban.
and the 29th King of Silla spent his leisure time shooting arrows into the passing clouds.
e il 29° re del regno di Silla passava il tempo libero scoccando frecce alle nubi di passaggio.
dan Raja Silla ke-29 menghabiskan waktu luangnya melepaskan anak panah ke awan yang lewat.
新羅の第 29 代の王が休暇を過ごし 過ぎゆく雲に矢を放った景勝地
新羅的第 29 代君主也曾在此彎弓射雲 度過悠閒的時光
第 29 代新羅王亦最愛來此消閒 把箭射進天上飄過的白雲
และเป็นสถานที่โปรดของพระเจ้าซิลลาองค์ที่ 29 สำหรับการผ่อนคลายจากภาระหน้าที่
e o 29ª rei de Silla passava o tempo atirando flechas nas nuvens.
le 29e roi de la dynastie de Silla tirait des flèches dans les nuages pour passer le temps.
et où le 29e roi de Silla se divertissait en tirant des flèches dans les nuages.
Täällä myös Sillan valtakunnan 29. kuningas tapasi huvitella ampumalla nuolia ohi lipuviin pilviin.
오늘날에도 비록 신선은 아니지만
Voor de stervelingen van vandaag
For dagens dødelige
I dag er parken perfekt til dem,
Für die Sterblichen von heute ist der Park
Còn với trần thế hôm nay,
För dagens vanliga dödliga
Para los simples mortales de hoy,
Actualmente,
For today’s mere mortals,
Per i semplici mortali di oggi,
Untuk manusia masa kini,
日常の雑踏を離れ
對現代人來說
對於今天我們凡人
สำหรับเหล่ามนุษย์ในปัจจุบัน
Hoje em dia,
Pour le simple mortel d’aujourd’hui,
Pour le commun des mortels,
Tätä nykyä
누구나 저 멀리 항구를 드나드는 화물선을 바라보며 마음의 위안을 찾기에
is het park de ideale plek om het rustig aan te doen
er parken det perfekte stedet for å koble av
som ønsker at geare ned og og finde indre ro,
ideal, um Körper und Geist auszuruhen und dabei den Frachtschiffen zuzusehen,
công viên là điểm hẹn tuyệt vời để buông bỏ sầu lo, thả hồn theo
är parken den perfekta platsen för att sjunka ner i lugna tankar
el parque es el lugar perfecto para entrar en un estado de relajación
el parque es el lugar perfecto para tomarse la vida con calma
the park's the perfect place to slip into a slower state of mind
il parco è il posto perfetto per dimenticare ogni pensiero
taman ini merupakan tempat yang tepat untuk masuk ke keadaan pikiran yang lebih tenang
この公園に時を忘れて ゆったりとした心で過ごします
來到這裡，欣賞貨船緩緩駛向遠方的港口 更是舒緩心情
這公園最適合 讓大家放慢節奏
สวนสาธารณะของที่นี่ช่างเพอร์เฟกต์ สำหรับการผ่อนคลายอารมณ์
o parque é um lugar perfeito para desacelerar
le parc est l’endroit idéal pour ralentir la cadence
c'est un endroit idéal pour arrêter le temps,
Taejongdaen puisto on loistava paikka rauhoittaa mieli
적합한 장소이지요.
terwijl vrachtschepen naar verre havens varen.
og se på lasteskipene som drar avgårde.
mens skibene langsomt sejler forbi.
wie sie ferne Häfen ansteuern.
đoàn tàu chở hàng tới những bến cảng xa xôi.
under tiden som fraktfartyg glider iväg mot avlägsna hamnar.
mientras los barcos de carga viajan hacia puertos lejanos.
mientras los cargueros parten hacia puertos lejanos.
as cargo ships journey to far off ports.
osservando le navi mercantili dirette in porti lontani.
perjalanan kapal kargo ke pelabuhan yang jauh.
海の彼方に向かう船のように
放慢生活步調的好選擇
觀看貨船駛向遠處港口
เนื่องจากเรือสินค้าไม่ได้เฉียดใกล้ที่นี่เลย
vendo navios passando no horizonte.
et regarder les cargos s’éloigner en haute mer.
alors que les cargos s'en vont vers des ports lointains.
rahtilaivojen lipuessa kohti kaukomaita.
이렇게 차분한 분위기는 송도 해수욕장까지 이어집니다.
De meditatieve sfeer gaat verder op het strand Songdo.
Songdo strand kan by på mer meditativ stemning.
Den meditative atmosfære fortsætter ved Songdo Strand.
Einen fast meditativen Zustand erreicht man auch
Bầu không khí an nhiên cũng bao phủ Bãi biển Songdo.
Sinnesron dröjer sig kvar på Songdo Beach.
Este estado de ánimo meditativo también se encuentra en playa Songdo.
Continúa con la meditación en la playa de Songdo.
The meditative mood continues at Songdo Beach.
L’atmosfera meditativa prosegue sulla spiaggia di Songdo.
Suasana meditatif berlanjut di Pantai Songdo.
松島ビーチにも 清らかな空気が満ちています
松島海水浴場是另一個潛思冥想的好去處
要繼續沉思的話，可到松島海水浴場
ความสงบยังมีต่อที่ชายหาดซองโด
O clima de meditação continua na Praia de Songdo.
La plage Songdo baigne aussi dans la tranquillité.
La plage de Songdo est aussi propice à la méditation.
Myös Songdon rannalla vallitsee rauhallinen tunnelma.
바다 위에 떠 있는 산책길을 걸으며 경치를 즐겨보세요.
Wandel boven het golvende water op het verhoogde voetpad,
Gå over det virvlende vannet på gangbroen
Gå på tværs af det hvirvlende vand højt oppe på gangstien,
am Strand von Songdo, dessen Strandpromenade über dem Wasser schwebt.
Lối đi xây cao bắc ngang vùng nước đang cuộn chảy
Vandra ut över det skummande havet utmed det högt belägna vandringsstråket,
Atraviesa las aguas turbulentas por el puente elevado,
Cruza las aguas revueltas sobre la pasarela elevada,
Step across the swirling waters on the elevated walkway,
Superate le sue acque vorticose grazie alla passerella sopraelevata,
Berjalan di atas air yang berombak di jalan setapak yang tinggi,
渦潮を海上ウォークウェイから 眺めます
踏上造型盤曲有如潛蛟出洞的 天空步道
踏過建在旋轉的海水 之上的步道
เดินชมน้ำวนบนสะพานที่ยกตัวสูงขึ้น จากทะเล
Caminhe sobre as águas tranquilas usando a passarela
Traversez les eaux tourbillonnantes en empruntant la passerelle surélevée
Une promenade surélevée traverse les eaux,
Astele lainehtivan veden yllä kohoavalle kävelylaiturille,
이 산책로의 곡선 형태는 바닷가 동굴에 사는 신화 속 용이 하늘로 솟아오르는 모양을 나타낸다고 해요.
dat met zijn bochten lijkt op een mythische draak die vanuit zijn nest aan de kust uitvliegt.
som minner om en mytisk drage som flyr avgårde fra hiet sitt på kysten.
hvis form afbilder en mytisk drage og flugter ud i de kystlige vinde.
Die geschwungene Form erinnert an einen Drachen, der zum Flug ansetzt.
thấp thoáng những đường cong tái hiện cảnh mãnh long trong truyền thuyết vút bay từ hang rồng ven biển.
vars kurvor föreställer en mytomspunnen drake som är på väg att flyga upp från sin kustlya.
cuyas curvas representan un dragón mítico emprendiendo vuelo desde su guarida costera.
cuyas curvas forman un dragón mítico que levantan el vuelo de su refugio costero.
whose curves depict a mythical dragon taking flight from it’s coastal lair.
le cui curve raffigurano un drago mitologico che spicca il volo dalla sua tana costiera.
yang berkelok menggambarkan mitos naga yang terbang dari sarangnya di pesisir pantai.
これは伝説の龍が海辺から 飛び立つ姿を表しています
凌空橫渡起伏不定的 洶湧波濤
欣賞彎曲的步道像傳說中 正逃離岸邊洞穴的飛龍
ซึ่งดูแล้วคล้ายกับมังกรในตำนาน กำลังโบยบินขึ้นจากชายฝั่งสู่ผืนฟ้า
formada por curvas que lembram um dragão levantando voo do litoral.
qui ondule comme un dragon mythique s’envolant de son nid en bord de mer.
selon la forme d'un dragon prenant son envol depuis la côte.
jonka mutkat jäljittelevät rantaluolasta lentoon lähtevää lohikäärmettä.
이제 다대포 해수욕장으로 가서 마음이 닿는 대로 거닐어 보세요.
Laat je gedachten de vrije loop en je kinderen lekker spelen aan het strand Dadaepo.
La tankene fly og barna løpe fritt på Dadaepo strand.
Lad derefter tankerne og børnene løbe frit på Dadaepo Strand.
Lassen Sie anschließend Ihren Gedanken – und Ihren Kindern – am Strand von Dadaepo freien Lauf.
Đến Bãi biển Dadaepo, khi cha mẹ tranh thủ thư giãn thì bọn trẻ chạy nhảy nô đùa khắp chốn.
Dröm dig sedan bort och låt barnen leka fritt på Dadaepo Beach.
Luego, deja que tu mente deambule y que los niños corran libremente en la playa Dadaepo.
Después, deja vagar la mente y a los niños correr a sus anchas en la playa de Dadaepo.
Then, let your mind wander and the kids run free at Dadaepo Beach.
Lasciate quindi vagare la mente mentre i più piccoli corrono felici sulla spiaggia Dadaepo.
Lalu, biarkan pikiran Anda berkelana dan anak-anak berlarian bebas di Pantai Dadaepo.
多大浦ビーチは大人の休憩所 子どもの壮大な遊び場
好好享受神遊物外的快感，小朋友也能 在多大浦海灘上盡情嬉戲
來到多大浦海水浴場您大可放鬆心情 讓小孩自由奔跑
จากนั้นปลดปล่อยอารมณ์และพาเด็กๆ ไปวิ่งเล่น ที่หาดดาแดโป
Relaxe e deixe as crianças se divertirem na Praia de Dadaepo.
Puis laissez s’évader votre esprit et courir les enfants sur la plage de Dadaepo.
Vous laisserez librement courir vos enfants et vos pensées sur la plage de Dadaepo.
Anna mielesi vaeltaa ja lasten juosta vapaana Dadaepon rannalla.
다대포 해수욕장은 우리나라에서 가장 긴 낙동강 하구에 있습니다.
Hier aan de monding van Zuid-Korea’s langste rivier
Her, ved munnen av Sør-Koreas lengste elv,
Her ved udmundingen af Sydkoreas længste flod,
Hier, an der Mündung des längsten Flusses
Chính đây, cửa con sông dài nhất Hàn Quốc,
Här, vid mynningen av Sydkoreas längsta flod,
Aquí, en la desembocadura del río más largo de Corea del Sur,
En la boca del río más largo de Corea del Sur,
Here, at the mouth of South Korea’s longest river,
Qui, alla foce del fiume più lungo della Corea del Sud,
Di sini, di muara sungai terpanjang di Korea Selatan,
韓国で最も長い川の河口であり
這裡是韓國最長河流的出海口
這裡是南韓最長的河流河口
ที่นี่คือปากน้ำของแม่น้ำที่ยาวที่สุดในเกาหลี
Na foz do maior rio da Coreia de Sul,
Ici, à l’embouchure de la plus longue rivière
À l'embouchure du plus long fleuve du pays,
Täällä, Etelä-Korean pisimmän joen suulla,
이곳의 끝없이 펼쳐진 모래와 해무는 해안선을 흐릿하게 만들어 천국과 지상의 경계를 모호하게 만들죠.
kun je door het eindeloze zand en de zeemist haast het verschil tussen hemel en aarde niet meer zien.
visker den endeløse sanden og havet ut linjene mellom himmel og jord.
mødes det bløde sand og de milde havvinde mellem himmel og jord.
von Südkorea, verschwimmen die Grenzen zwischen Himmel und Erde.
cát trải miên man và sương mù vùng biển như xóa nhòa ranh giới giữa đất trời.
suddar de oändliga stränderna och havsdimmorna ut skiljelinjen mellan himmel och jord.
las interminables arenas y nieblas marinas desdibujan las líneas entre el cielo y la tierra.
las arenas infinitas y la bruma marina difuminan la línea entre el cielo y la tierra.
the endless sands and sea mists blur the lines between heaven and earth.
la sabbia infinita e la foschia marina confondono il tenue confine fra la terra e il paradiso.
pasir tak berujung dan kabut pantai mengaburkan garis antara surga dan dunia.
どこまでも続く砂浜と海霧 ここは天国でしょうか
綿延不盡的沙灘和霧氣迷濛的大海 構成海天一色的絕美勝景
一望無際的沙灘和海上升起的霧 讓您分不出天或地
มีผืนทรายยาวเหยียดและหมอกสีขาว เชื่อมโลกมนุษย์และสวรรค์ไว้ด้วยกัน
as faixas de areia e a névoa do mar se fundem na paisagem.
de la Corée du Sud, la ligne d’horizon s’estompe et ciel et mer ne font plus qu’un.
le sable et la brume marine lui confèrent un air de paradis.
loputon hiekka ja meriutu saavat meren ja taivaan sulautumaan yhteen.
부산과 바다는 떼려야 뗄 수 없는 관계이지만 주변을 둘러싼 산들도
Hoewel de geschiedenis van Busan steeds door de zee is gevormd,
Busans historie har kontinuerlig blitt formet av havet,
Selvom Busans historie i høj grad er præget af havet,
Obwohl Busans Geschichte maßgeblich vom Meer geprägt ist,
Dẫu biết Busan xưa nay chẳng tách rời biển cả,
Pusans historia har ständigt formats av havet,
Aunque la historia de Busan ha sido continuamente moldeada por el mar,
Aunque la historia de Busan siempre ha estado influenciada por el mar,
While Busan’s story has been continually shaped by the sea,
Anche se la storia di Busan è stata sempre plasmata dal mare,
Meski kisah tentang Busan terus dibentuk oleh laut,
プサンの歴史はずっと 海が形作ってきましたが
雖然釜山的發展與海洋 息息相關
儘管釜山的故事一直 離不開海洋
เรื่องราวของปูซานมักจะเกี่ยวข้อง กับทะเลอยู่ตลอด
Busan tem sua história muito ligada ao mar,
Certes, l’océan a toujours influencé l’histoire de Pusan,
Si l'histoire de Busan est étroitement liée à la mer,
Vaikka merellä on ollut Busanin historiassa merkittävä rooli,
들려줄 이야기가 많습니다.
staat de stad net zo bekend om zijn bergen.
men byen er i like stor grad preget av fjellene sine.
er byen i ligeså stor en grad defineret af dens bjerge.
sind auch die Berge immer präsent.
thế nhưng thành phố cũng in dấu núi non.
men staden har formats lika mycket av sina berg.
a esta ciudad también la definen sus montañas.
las montañas también son importantes en la ciudad.
it’s a city equally defined by its mountains.
le montagne sono altrettanto importanti per la città.
Busan adalah kota yang juga dibentuk oleh pegunungannya.
山も街の名物です
綿延縱伸的山脈也是當地的一大特色
但群山對釜山同樣重要
แต่ที่เด่นไม่แพ้กันคือภูมิประเทศที่เป็นภูเขา
mas também às montanhas.
mais les montagnes ont aussi joué un rôle majeur.
la ville est aussi célèbre pour ses montagnes.
kaupunki on kuuluisa myös vuoristaan.
항구 바로 위쪽으로
Net boven de haven kun je
Like over havnen
Tag rulletrappen til bjergtoppen af Yongdusan Park
Direkt über dem Hafen fährt
Ngay phía trên bến cảng,
Precis ovanför hamnen
Justo arriba del puerto,
Justo sobre el puerto,
Just above the port,
Proprio sopra al porto,
Di atas pelabuhan,
港のすぐ上に
來到港口上方
就在海港之上
ที่ด้านบนของท่าเรือ
Logo depois do porto,
Juste au-dessus du port,
Sataman läheltä
에스컬레이터를 타고 올라가면
met de roltrap naar de top van het Yongdusan-park
kan du ta rulletrapp til toppen av Yongdusan-parken
som befinder sig over havnen,
eine Rolltreppe zur Spitze des Yongdusan-Parks.
hệ thống thang máy chạy thẳng lên đỉnh Công viên Yongdusan,
kan du ta rulltrappan mot toppen av Yongdusan Park,
sube por las escaleras eléctricas hasta la cima del parque Yongdusan
sube las escaleras hasta la cima del parque de Yongdusan
ride the escalator to the summit of Yongdusan Park
prendete la scala mobile verso la cima del parco Yongdusan
naik eskalator ke puncak Taman Yongdusan
エスカレーターで龍頭山公園の頂上へ
搭乘手扶梯前往龍頭山公園的山頂
您可乘自動樓梯登上龍頭山公園山頂
คุณสามารถขึ้นบันไดเลื่อนไปที่อุทยานยงดูซาน
pegue a escada rolante para o topo do parque
prenez l’escalier roulant jusqu’au parc Yongdusan.
un escalator mène au sommet de Yongdusan Park,
lähtevät liukuportaat Yongdusanin puiston laelle.
용두산공원 정상에 도착하게 돼요. 이곳에는 16세기 해상 영웅인
en het uitzicht delen met het standbeeld van de 16e-eeuwse zeeheld
og nyte den samme utsikten som statuen av sjøhelten fra 1500-tallet,
og nyd udsigten sammen med statuen af den maritime helt fra det 16. århundrede,
Hier steht die Statue des brillantesten Militärstrategen aus dem 16. Jahrhundert,
đưa du khách đến ngắm bao cảnh đẹp trải rộng trước bức tượng anh hùng hải quân thế kỷ 16,
och beundra utsikten tillsammans med statyn av amiralen Yi Sun Sin,
y comparte las vistas con la estatua del héroe naval del siglo XIX,
y comparte las vistas con la estatua del almirante Yi Sun Sin,
and share the views with the statue of 16th century naval hero,
e ammirate il panorama in compagnia della statua dell’eroe navale del 16° secolo,
dan nikmati pemandangan dengan patung dari pahlawan angkatan laut abad ke-16,
景色とともに 16 世紀 豊臣秀吉と戦った
就能俯瞰釜山的市容，16 世紀海軍名將 李舜臣的雕像
跟 16 世紀海上英雄 李舜臣將軍的雕像
ชมวิวสวยๆ และประติมากรรมฮีโร่ จากศตวรรษที่ 16
Yongdusan, admire as paisagens e a estátua do herói naval do século 16,
Profitez de la vue aux côtés de la statue d’un héros de la marine du XVIe siècle,
avec ses vues exceptionnelles et la statue du héros marin du XVIe siècle,
Siellä voit ihailla maisemia yhdessä 1500-luvun merisankarin,
이순신 장군의 동상이 세워져 있습니다.
admiraal Yi Sun Sin.
Admiral Yi Sun Sin.
Đô đốc Yi Sun Sin.
en hjälte i den koreanska flottan på 1500-talet.
el almirante Yi Sun Sin.
héroe naval del siglo XVI.
Admiral Yi Sun Sin.
l’Ammiraglio Yi Sun Sin.
Laksamana Yi Sun Sin.
李舜臣将軍像がそびえます
也屹立於此
一起飽覽美景
พลเรือเอกยีซุนซิน
Admiral Yi Sun Sin.
l’amiral Yi Sun Sin.
l'amiral Yi Sun Sin.
amiraali Yi Sun-sinin, kanssa.
근처에 있는 천마산에서는
Op de Cheonma-berg vlak bij
På fjellet Cheonma som ligger i nærheten
Gå en tur på 20 minutter op til udkigsposten
Die Aussichtsplattform auf dem
Trên Núi Cheonma gần kề,
På berget Cheonmasan i närheten
En el cercano monte Cheonma,
En el cercano monte de Cheonma,
On nearby Mt Cheonma,
Dal vicino monte Cheonma
Di dekat Gunung Cheonma,
天摩山を 20 分 ほど歩くと
來到鄰近的天摩山
在附近的天摩山
ขยับไปที่เขาชอนมา
Na montanha Cheonma,
Sur le mont voisin de Cheonma,
Le mont Cheonma voisin offre une
Läheiseltä Cheonman vuorelta
20분이면 오를 수 있는 전망대에 가 보세요. '다이나믹한 부산'의 면모가
kom je met een wandeling van 20 minuten op het uitkijkplatform waar ‘dynamisch Busan’
kan du ta en 20 minutters gåtur til utkikksplatået og se «dynamiske Busan»
på det nærliggende bjerg Cheonma, og beundr Busans dynamiske hverdag
nahe gelegenen Berg Cheonma ist zu Fuß in 20 Minuten erreicht und
chỉ mất 20 phút thôi là ta sẽ tới đài quan sát, để thấy “Busan năng động”
kan du ta en 20 minuters vandringstur upp till utsiktsplatsen för att se ”dynamiska Pusan”
camina 20 minutos hasta llegar al mirador para ver a la ciudad dinámica de Busan
haz un recorrido de 20 minutos hasta el puesto de observación para ver "Dynamic Busan"
take the 20-minute hike to the observation platform to see “Dynamic Busan”
seguite per circa 20 minuti il percorso che vi porterà a una piattaforma dove potrete osservare la “Dynamic Busan”
mendakilah 20 menit ke platform observasi untuk melihat “Busan yang Dinamis”
展望台がお出迎え ダイナミックなプサンの姿が
花 20 分鐘的時間登上觀景台 活力十足的釜山
您可花 20 分鐘時間 到觀景台欣賞在您面前
เดินขึ้นเขาประมาณ 20 นาทีไปยังจุดชมวิว ที่คุณจะได้เห็นความเป็นไปของซูซาน
faça a trilha de 20 minutos até a plataforma de observação para ter
une randonnée de 20 minutes vous mène à la plate-forme d’observation qui offre
plate-forme d'observation, accessible en 20 minutes à pied, sur l'ensemble de
löytyy sieltäkin näköalatasanne, jolta voit nähdä alati muuttuvan Busanin
고스란히 눈 앞에 펼쳐질 거예요.
zich voor je uitspreidt.
strekke seg ut foran deg.
foran dine fødder.
bietet einen tollen Blick auf Busan.
khoe mình trọn vẹn.
breda ut sig framför dig.
frente a ti.
a tus pies.
spread out before you.
che si estende davanti ai vostri occhi.
membentang di hadapan Anda.
目の前に広がります
就能盡收眼底
展現的《活力釜山》
ตามสโลแกน "ไดนามิก ปูซาน"
uma bela vista de Busan.
à voir le visage dynamique de Pusan.
« Busan la dynamique ».
leviävän edessäsi.
북쪽에 자리한
In het noorden van de stad
Nord i byen
I den nordlige del af byen,
Im Norden der Stadt
Phía bắc thành phố,
I stadens norra del
En el norte de la ciudad,
Al norte de la ciudad,
In the city’s north,
Nella parte nord della città
Di bagian utara kota,
プサン北部にある
來到市區北邊
在釜山的北面
ทางตอนเหนือของเมือง
Ao norte da cidade,
Au nord de la ville,
Kaupungin pohjoisosassa
부산에서 가장 높은 봉우리인 금강공원으로 가볼까요? 케이블카를 타고 5분 정도만 올라가면
ben je met de kabelbaan binnen 5 minuten in het Geumjeong-park,
kan du ta en fem minutters tur med taubane til Geumgang-parken,
kan du tage kabelbanen og opleve Geumgang Park, som ligger sig blot fem minutter væk,
bringt Sie eine Seilbahn in fünf Minuten zum Geumgang-Park,
xe cáp treo chỉ chạy khoảng năm phút là tới Công viên Geumgang,
kan du ta en fem minuters åktur med linbana till Geumgang Park,
sube a bordo de un teleférico durante cinco minutos para llegar al parque Geumgang,
móntate en el teleférico para disfrutar de un trayecto de cinco minutos hasta el parque de Geumgang,
climb aboard a cable car for the five-minute ride to Geumgang Park,
salite su una funivia che vi condurrà, in circa cinque minuti, al parco Geumgang,
naik kereta gantung selama lima menit ke Taman Geumgang,
5 分ほどケーブル カーを楽しむと プサン最高峰の
只要搭乘五分鐘的纜車 就會抵達金剛公園
您可乘搭纜車 5 分鐘便 可去到金剛公園
ขึ้นเคเบิลคาร์ไปยังสวนกึมกัง โดยใช้เวลาเพียง 5 นาที
pegue o bondinho até o parque Geumgang,
un véhicule tracté par câble vous mène en 5 minutes au parc Geumgang,
un trajet de 5 minutes en tramway mène à Geumgang Park,
voit nousta gondolihissiin ja ajaa viisi minuuttia Geumgangin puistoon,
도착할 수 있는 이곳에서는
waar je het hoogste punt van Busan vindt.
hvor du finner Busans høyeste topp.
og du befinder dig på Busans højeste punkt.
wo sich der höchste Berg Busans befindet.
nơi có đỉnh núi cao nhất Busan.
hemvisten för Pusans högsta bergstopp.
donde se encuentra el pico más alto de Busan.
hogar del pico más alto de Busan.
the home to Busan’s highest peak.
dove si trova la cima più alta di Busan.
rumah bagi puncak tertinggi di Busan.
金鋼公園に着きます
也是釜山最高峰的所在處
釜山最高山峰便在這裡
ยอดเขาที่สูงที่สุดของปูซานอยู่ที่นี่เอง
que fica no ponto mais alto de Busan.
qui abrite le plus haut sommet de Pusan.
qui abrite le point culminant de Busan.
jossa sijaitsee Busanin korkein kohta.
매주 수천 명의 주민이 모여 금정산성을 둘러싼
Sluit je aan bij de duizenden inwoners die hier elk weekend wandelen
Hit drar tusenvis av lokale på tur hver helg
Gør som tusinder af de lokale, og vandr derop hver weekend
Tausende Einheimische wandern hier jedes Wochenende auf den
Dân bản xứ đổ về đây dạo bộ mỗi cuối tuần có tới hàng ngàn người,
Följ fotspåren av alla tusentals lokalbor som kommer hit för att vandra på helgen,
Acompaña a los miles de residentes que caminan aquí cada fin de semana
Únete a miles de residentes que pasean por la zona los fines de semana
Join the thousands of locals who hike here each weekend,
Unitevi alle migliaia di persone della zona che ogni fine settimana la scelgono come meta per le escursioni,
Bergabunglah dengan ribuan warga lokal yang mendaki di sini setiap akhir pekan,
週末に訪れる多くの地元住民と 山を歩いてみませんか
每週末來此登山健行的民眾 不計其數
每逢周末數以千計的當地人 來此遠足
เดินขึ้นเขาพร้อมกับนักปีนเขาท้องถิ่นที่แวะเวียนมา ทุกสุดสัปดาห์
Junte-se aos locais que visitam o parque aos fins de semana
Joignez-vous aux milliers d’habitants qui y viennent chaque fin de semaine
Chaque week-end, des milliers d'habitants s'y rendent pour
Tuhannet paikalliset tulevat tänne vaeltamaan joka viikonloppu
숲속 산책로와 성벽길을 따라 하이킹을 즐기는 모습이 펼쳐지죠.
om de bospaden en de muren van het kasteel Geumjeongsanseong te verkennen.
for å utforske skogsstiene og veggene til Geumgang-festningen.
for at udforske skovens snoede stier og Geumgang Borg.
Waldwanderwegen und entlang der Mauern der Festung Geumgang.
những con đường rừng và tường thành thuộc Pháo đài Geumgang càng làm cảnh quan thêm kỳ vĩ.
och utforska skogsstigarna och murarna av Geumgangs fästning.
y exploran los muros y los senderos del bosque de la Fortaleza de Geumgang.
y explora los senderos y los muros de la fortaleza de Geumjeong.
exploring the forest trails and walls of Geumgang Fortress.
esplorando i sentieri immersi nel verde e le mura della fortezza di Geumgang.
menjelajahi jalan setapak hutan dan tembok Benteng Geumgang.
遊歩道や金井山城の 壁を散策します
您也可以來此，深入探索 金井山城的森林步道與城牆
探索金剛城附近 森林裡的山徑和城牆
สำรวจเส้นทางเดินเขา และกำแพงป้อมกึมกัง
para explorar as trilhas e as paredes do Forte Geumgang.
pour sillonner les sentiers de la forêt et explorer les murs de la forteresse Geumgang.
explorer les sentiers et les murailles de la forteresse de Geumgang.
tutkien metsäpolkuja sekä Geumgangin linnakkeen muureja.
금강공원에는 범어사도 자리하고 있는데요.
In het park staat ook de Beomeosa-tempel,
I parken finner du også Beomeosa-tempelet,
Parken er også hjemsted for Beomeosa Tempel,
Im Park befindet sich auch
Chùa Beomeosa trong công viên từng có
I parken hittar du också Beomeosa-templet,
También en el parque está el templo Beomeosa,
El parque también alberga el templo de Beomeosa,
The park is also home to Beomeosa Temple,
Qui c'è anche il tempio di Beomeosa,
Taman ini juga merupakan rumah bagi Kuil Beomeosa,
ここは梵魚寺のお膝元でもあり
這個公園也是梵魚寺的所在地
這公園亦是梵魚寺所在
นอกจากนี้ ที่นี่ยังเป็นที่ตั้งของวัดเบียวเมียวซา
O parque também abriga o Templo de Beomeosa,
Le parc abrite aussi le temple Beomeosa.
C'est là que se trouve le temple de Beomeosa,
Puistosta löytyy myös Beomeosan temppeli,
이곳에서 수행했던 승려들은 16세기 임진왜란 때는 침략자들에 대항했고
waarvan de krijgsmonniken in de 16e eeuw en later in de 20e eeuw
der krigsmunker nedkjempet inntrengere først på 1500-tallet,
hvis krigeriske munke kæmpede mod indtrængende fjender i det 16. århundrede
der Beomeosa-Tempel, dessen Kriegermönche im 16. und 20. Jahrhundert
các nhà sư chiến đấu chống quân xâm lược trong thế kỷ 16
vars krigarmunkar stred för att värja sig mot inkräktare på 1500-talet,
cuyos monjes guerreros lucharon contra los invasores en el siglo XVI
cuyos monjes lucharon contra los invasores durante el siglo XVI
whose warrior monks fought off invaders in the 16th century,
casa dei monaci guerrieri che hanno combattuto e respinto gli invasori nel 16° secolo
yang biksu prajuritnya berjuang melawan penjajah di abad ke-16,
16 世紀と 20 世紀に この寺の僧兵たちが
寺內的武僧在 16 世紀和 20 世紀時 曾奮勇禦敵
寺內的戰士僧侶在 16 世紀時奮勇 打退侵略者
ที่ครั้งหนึ่งนักบวชต้องสวมวิญญาณนักรบ ต่อสู้กับผู้รุกราน ในศตวรรษที่ 16
cujos monges lutaram contra invasores nos séculos
Ses moines guerriers ont vaincu les envahisseurs au XVIe siècle,
dont les moines ont repoussé les envahisseurs au XVIe siècle,
jonka munkit kukistivat ulkomaiset valloittajat 1500-luvulla
20세기에 다시 한번 독립만세운동에 참여했어요.
indringers wisten te verslaan.
og deretter på 1900-tallet.
og igen i det 20. århundrede.
Invasoren abwehrten.
và sau đó là vào thế kỷ 20.
och återigen på 1900-talet.
y otra vez en el siglo XX.
y de nuevo en el XX.
and again in the 20th.
e poi di nuovo nel 20°.
dan lagi di abad ke-20.
外敵と戦いました
擊退入侵本寺的敵寇
在 20 世紀又再展英魂
และศตวรรษที่ 20
16 e 20.
puis de nouveau au XXe siècle.
mais aussi au XXe.
ja myös 1900-luvulla.
부산은 영웅들을 결코 잊지 않는 도시입니다. 근처 충렬사는
Busan vergeet zijn helden nooit en bij de Chungnyeolsa-tempel in de buurt
Busan glemmer aldri heltene sine, og på Chungnyeolsa-tempelet i nærheten
Busan glemmer ikke sine helte, og i det nærliggende Chungnyeolsa Tempel
Busan vergisst seine Helden nicht und im nahe gelegenen Chungnyeolsa-Tempel
Busan muôn đời ghi công các anh hùng, Chùa Chungnyeolsa gần đó
Pusan glömmer aldrig sina hjältar, och i närheten av Chungnyeolsa-templet
Busan nunca olvida a sus héroes, y en el cercano templo Chungnyeolsa,
Busan no olvida a sus héroes, y en el cercano templo de Chungnyeolsa
Busan never forgets its heroes, and at nearby Chungnyeolsa Temple,
Busan non dimentica i suoi eroi e nel vicino tempio di Chungnyeolsa
Busan tidak pernah melupakan pahlawannya, dan di dekatnya terdapat Kuil Chungnyeolsa,
この英雄たちはプサンの誇りです 忠烈祠付近では
對於先賢的犧牲奉獻，釜山永誌不忘 前往附近的忠烈祠
釜山從不忘記一眾英雄，您可到 附近的忠烈祠
ชาวปูซานไม่เคยลืมวีรบุรุษในอดีต ที่ศาลเจ้าชุงนีโยลซา
Busan valoriza os seus heróis e, no Templo Chungnyeolsa,
Pusan n’oublie jamais ses héros. Dans les environs, au temple Chungnyeolsa,
Busan honore ses héros : le temple de Chungnyeolsa
Busan ei unohda sankareitaan, ja läheinen Chungnyeolsan pyhäkkö
1592년 도시가 일본군에게 포위되었을 당시 자신의 목숨마저 기꺼이 희생했던
kun je stilstaan bij de herinnering aan de patriotten van Busan, die hun leven hebben gegeven
kan du vise din respekt til Busans patrioter som ofret livene sine
kan du vise din respekt til Busans patrioters ånder, som ofrede deres liv,
wird der Patrioten gedacht, die ihr Leben ließen, als die Stadt 1592
mãi dành trọn niềm tôn kính cho hương hồn những người con ái quốc của Busan đã hi sinh
kan du besöka gravplatsen för de soldater som dog när de försvarade sin hemstad
rinde respeto a los espíritus de los patriotas de Busan que perdieron la vida
podrás presentar tus respetos a las almas de los patriotas que dieron su vida
pay your respects to the spirits of Busan’s patriots who gave their lives
potrete porgere i vostri omaggi agli spiriti dei patrioti di Busan che sacrificarono la loro vita
berkunjunglah untuk memberi penghormatan kepada jiwa-jiwa pahlawan Busan yang mengorbankan hidupnya
1592 年にプサンを攻めた 秀吉軍との戦いに
就能追憶在 1592 年 壬辰倭亂期間
向在 1592 年日軍攻城時 犠牲自己的性命
คือที่ที่คุณสามารถไปสักการะ วิญญาณวีรบุรุษของปูซาน
homenageia o espírito dos patriotas que lutaram até a morte
rendez hommage à ces patriotes qui ont donné leur vie en 1592
est ainsi dédié aux esprits des patriotes de Busan qui ont péri lors du siège
on omistettu niille Busanin urheille asukkaille, jotka uhrasivat henkensä
부산 애국자들의 영혼을 기리는 장소입니다.
toen de stad in 1592 door Japanse troepen werd belegerd.
da byen deres ble beleiret av japanske tropper i 1592.
dengang byen blev bestormet af japanske tropper i 1592.
von japanischen Truppen belagert wurde.
khi thành phố quê hương bị quân Nhật bao vây năm 1592.
mot belägrande japanska trupper 1592.
cuando su ciudad fue sitiada por tropas japonesas en 1592.
cuando la ciudad fue cercada por las tropas japonesas en 1592.
when their city was besieged by Japanese troops in 1592.
quando la città venne assediata dalle truppe giapponesi nel 1592.
ketika kota mereka dikepung oleh pasukan Jepang pada tahun 1592.
命をかけた 民の思いを感じます
為抵抗日軍入侵而殉國的志士，向這些 英靈致敬
捍衞家園的英雄 致敬
ผู้เสียสละชีวิตปกป้องดินแดนจากการรุกรานของกองทัพญี่ปุ่น ในปี 1592
quando a cidade foi sitiada por tropas japonesas em 1592.
lorsque les troupes japonaises ont assiégé leur ville.
par les troupes japonaises en 1592.
kaupungin jäätyä japanilaisten piirittämäksi vuonna 1592.
1950년, 부산은 또 한 번 포위되는 위험의 순간을 맞이했는데요.
In 1950 werd Busan opnieuw belegerd.
I 1950 ble Busan beleiret nok en gang.
I 1950 blev Busan igen belejret.
1950 wurde Busan erneut belagert.
Năm 1950, Busan lại một lần nữa rơi vào vòng vây hãm.
År 1950 hamnade Pusan under belägring ännu en gång.
En 1950, Busan volvió a estar bajo asedio.
En 1950, Busan volvió a ser asediada.
In 1950, Busan was again under siege.
Nel 1950, Busan finì di nuovo sotto assedio.
Pada tahun 1950, Busan kembali dikepung.
1950 年にもプサンは攻撃されました
1950 年時，釜山再度陷入戰火
1950 年釜山再次被圍攻
และในปี 1950 ปูซานถูกล้อมไว้อีกครั้ง
Em 1950, Busan estava sitiada novamente.
En 1950, Pusan subissait un autre siège.
En 1950, Busan fut à nouveau assiégée.
Vuonna 1950 Busan oli jälleen piiritetty.
유엔기념공원에 들러
Bij de Erebegraafplaats Tanggok kun je
På FNs minnegravlund
Ved FN’s Mindesmærkegravplads
Auf dem UN Memorial Cemetery fanden
Nghĩa trang Tưởng niệm Liên Hiệp Quốc
Vid FN:s minneskyrkogård
En el cementerio conmemorativo de la ONU,
En el cementerio conmemorativo de la ONU
At the UN Memorial Cemetery,
Nel Cimitero memoriale delle Nazioni Unite
Di Makam Peringatan PBB,
UN 記念公園には
在韓聯合國紀念墓園
您可去到聯合國紀念墓地
ที่สุสานยูเอ็น
No Cemitério e Memorial da ONU,
Au cimetière commémoratif de l’ONU,
Le cimetière mémorial des Nations Unies
Vieraile YK:n hautausmaalla,
부산을 둘러싼 마지노선에서 북한군에 맞서 싸웠던
de graven bezoeken van een aantal van de 140.000 troepen
kan du besøke gravene til noen av de 140 000 soldatene
kan du opleve gravsteder fra nogle af de 140.000 tropper,
viele der 140.000 Soldaten ihre letzte Ruhe,
là nơi yên nghỉ của nhiều người trong 140.000 binh lính
kan du besöka gravarna tillhörande ca 140 000 stupade soldater,
visita las tumbas de algunos de los 140,000 soldados
podrás visitar las tumbas de algunos de los 140 000 soldados
visit the gravesites of some of the 140,000 troops
potrete osservare le tombe di alcuni dei 140.000 soldati
kunjungi sebagian makam dari 140.000 pasukan
戦死した約 14 万人の兵士が眠ります
是韓戰期間，為抵禦北韓入侵
在十四萬軍隊中部分軍人的墳前憑弔
คุณจะได้พบกับหลุมฝังศพของทหาร 140,000 นาย
visite as tumbas dos 140.000 combatentes
visitez les tombes des quelque 140 000 soldats
abrite les sépultures de quelques-uns des 140 000 soldats
jonne on haudattu 140 000 sotilasta.
14만여 명의 군인들이 잠들어 있는
die de laatste verdedigingslinie om Busan vormden
som formet en siste fortvilet forsvarslinje rundt Busan,
der danner en grøft omkring Busan,
die eine schmale Verteidigungslinie gegen
từng quyết giữ tuyến phòng thủ cuối cùng quanh Busan,
som konstruerade de sista skyttegravarna runt Pusan
que formaron un perímetro de última línea de defensa alrededor de Busan
que formaron un desesperado perímetro en torno a Busan
who formed a last-ditch perimeter around Busan,
che formarono un perimetro difensivo d’emergenza attorno a Busan,
yang membentuk parit perimeter terakhir di sekitar Busan,
北朝鮮の兵士が押し寄せ
參與釜山防禦圈戰役的 14 萬聯合國部隊
大軍當年誓死圍繞保衞釜山
ที่สู้จนตัวตายเพื่อปกป้องปูซาน
que se colocaram em volta de Busan
qui ont formé la dernière ligne défensive
qui ont défendu Busan et
Nämä sotilaat muodostivat Busanin ympärille piirin
묘지를 방문해 보세요.
toen ze tegen troepen van Noord-Koreaanse soldaten vochten.
som kjempet mot nord-koreanske soldater.
og som kæmpede mod nordkoreanske soldater.
den nordkoreanischen Vormarsch schützten.
chống trả lớp lớp quân Bắc Triều Tiên.
och slog tillbaka vågor av nordkoreanska soldater.
y lucharon contra oleadas de soldados norcoreanos.
y se enfrentaron a las tropas norcoreanas.
fighting off waves of North Korean soldiers.
cercando di respingere le armate nordcoreane.
melawan serbuan prajurit Korea Selatan.
プサンの要塞で激戦を繰り広げました
部分英靈的安息地
打退如浪潮湧來的北韓士兵
จากศึกสงครามกับทหารชาวเกาหลีเหนือ
para enfrentar os soldados da Coreia do Norte.
et repoussé les vagues de soldats nord-coréens.
repoussé les assauts de l'armée nord-coréenne.
torjuen hyökkäävät Pohjois-Korean joukot.
부산은 한국전쟁 당시 함락되지 않은 몇 안 되는 도시 중 하나로
Busan was een van de weinige zuidelijke steden die tijdens de Koreaanse Oorlog niet is gevallen, waardoor het
Busan var en av de få byene i sør som ikke falt under Koreakrigen,
Busan var en af de få sydlandske byer, som ikke faldt under den Koreakrigen,
Busan war eine der wenigen Städte im Süden, die im Koreakrieg nicht eingenommen wurde,
Busan nằm trong số ít các thành phố phương nam không bị nhấn chìm trong Chiến tranh Triều Tiên,
Pusan var en av de få sydkoreanska städer som inte föll under Koreakriget,
Busan fue una de las pocas ciudades del sur que no fue derrotada en la Guerra de Corea,
Busan fue una de las pocas ciudades del sur que no cayeron durante la guerra de Corea,
Busan was one of the few cities of the south not to fall during the Korean War,
Busan è stata una delle poche città della Corea del Sud a non cadere durante la guerra di Corea,
Busan adalah salah satu kota di selatan yang tidak jatuh selama Perang Korea,
プサンは 朝鮮戦争で陥落しなかった 韓国の数少ない都市です
在韓戰期間，釜山是南部少數 未淪陷的城市之一
釜山是當年在韓戰中幾個 沒有被攻陷的南韓城市之一
ปูซานคือหนึ่งในไม่กี่เมืองทางตอนใต้ ที่ไม่ล่มสลายไปในช่วงสงครามเกาหลี
Busan foi uma das poucas cidades do sul que resistiu durante a Guerra da Coreia,
Havre pour plus d’un demi-million de réfugiés, Pusan est l’une des seules villes du sud
Busan est l'une des rares villes du Sud à avoir résisté pendant la guerre de Corée,
Busan oli toinen Etelä-Korean kahdesta kaupungista, jota ei valloitettu Korean sodassa.
50만 명이 넘는 피난민들의 안전한 피난처 역할을 했어요.
voor ruim een half miljoen vluchtelingen een veilige haven werd.
og byen ble en trygg havn for over en halv million flyktninger.
og blev da et tilflugtssted for over en halv million flygtninge.
und gab so über einer halben Million Flüchtlinge Obdach.
trở thành chốn nương náu cho hơn nửa triệu dân tị nạn.
vilket gjorde staden till en tillflyktsort för mer än 500 000 krigsflyktingar.
convirtiéndose en un refugio seguro para más de medio millón de refugiados.
y acogió a más de medio millón de refugiados.
becoming a safe haven for over half a million refugees.
diventando un porto franco per oltre mezzo milione di rifugiati.
menjadi tempat yang aman bagi lebih dari setengah juta pengungsi.
プサンには 50 万人を超える人々が逃れました
也因此成為 50 多萬難民的避風港
更成為了超過 50 萬名難民的避難所
และกลายเป็นที่ลี้ภัยให้กับผู้อพยพกว่าครึ่งล้าน
abrigando mais de 500 mil refugiados.
à ne pas être tombées durant la guerre de Corée.
et elle a accueilli plus d'un million de réfugiés.
Niinpä sinne asettui yli puoli miljoonaa pakolaista.
유엔평화기념관에도 들러보세요.
In de United Nations Peace Memorial Hall
På FNs fredsminnesenter
Ved FN’s Peace Memorial Hall
In der UN Peace Memorial Hall
Nhà Tưởng niệm Hòa Bình Liên Hiệp Quốc
Vid UN Peace Memorial Hall
En la sala conmemorativa de la paz de la ONU,
En el Centro Conmemorativo de la Paz de la ONU
At the UN Peace Memorial Hall,
Nel Memoriale della pace delle Nazioni Unite
Di Aula Peringatan Perdamaian PBB,
UN 平和記念館は
聯合國和平紀念館
來到聯合國和平紀念館
ที่สุสานทหารสหประชาชาติ
No Salão do Memorial da Paz da ONU,
La salle commémorative de la paix de l’ONU
Le mémorial de la paix des Nations Unies
YK:n rauhanmuistomerkki
참전용사와 시민 희생자들을 기리고 있는 곳으로
worden de offers herdacht die zowel de krijgsmachten als de burgers hebben gebracht.
blir ofringer fra både militære og sivile husket,
mindes både krigere og civile samt de sørgelige historier
wird an die Opfer erinnert, die Soldaten und Zivilisten bringen mussten.
như lời nhắc nhở nhức nhối về sự hy sinh dẫu của binh lính hay thường dân,
hedras uppoffringarna av både soldater och civila,
los sacrificios tanto de combatientes como civiles son recordados,
se recuerda el sacrificio de los combatientes y los civiles,
the sacrifices of both combatants and civilians are remembered,
viene ricordato il sacrificio, sia dei soldati che dei civili,
pengorbanan dari pejuang dan warga sipil dikenang,
犠牲になった兵士と民間人を ともにしのびます
忠實記錄了戰士和平民百姓 所付出的犧牲
您可懷緬當年的軍人及平民 所作的犠牲
เป็นสถานที่รำลึกถึงทหารและพลเรือน ที่สละชีวิตในสงคราม
o sacrifício dos combatentes e dos civis é lembrado,
rend hommage aux sacrifices des combattants et des civils,
honore les sacrifices des combattants comme des civils,
on omistettu niin sotilaiden kuin siviilien tekemille uhrauksille,
전 세계적으로 진행 중인 여러 갈등으로 인해 고통받는 사람들에 대해 생각해 보는 시간이 될 거예요.
Ook worden de lijdensverhalen van voortdurende conflicten over de hele wereld herdacht.
i likhet med lidelsene fra pågående konflikter over hele verden.
fra vedvarende konflikter rundt om i verden.
Auch des Leids durch aktuelle Konflikte auf der Erde wird gedacht.
câu chuyện về sự thương đau mà các cuộc xung đột vẫn đang gieo rắc trên toàn cầu.
liksom berättelserna om lidandet från pågående konflikter runt jorden.
así como las historias de sufrimiento por los continuos conflictos en todo el mundo.
además de los relatos de sufrimiento de los conflictos inacabados de todo el mundo.
as are the stories of suffering from ongoing conflicts around the globe.
così come le storie delle sofferenze causate dai conflitti in tutto il mondo.
dan juga kisah-kisah penderitaan dari konflik yang sedang berlangsung di seluruh dunia.
今も世界で起こる争いに苦しむ 人々への思いに繋がります
也記述全球當前持續發生的 衝突與戰事
沉思全球各處因各種衝突 而面臨各種苦難的故事
นอกจากนี้ยังเป็นสถานที่แบ่งปันเรื่องราวที่มีผลจาก ความความขัดแย้งที่เกิดขึ้นทั่วโลก
bem como histórias de sofrimento de conflitos atuais no mundo.
et accueille les récits des autres conflits en cours partout sur la planète.
ainsi que ceux des populations qui souffrent au cœur des conflits actuels.
kuten myös muualla maailmassa riehuvien konfliktien uhreille.
부산은 피난민들로 인해 생겨난 고유의 문화가 많이 있습니다.
Busan heeft zijn veerkrachtige vluchtelingen veel te danken.
Busan skylder mye til sine utholdende flyktninger.
Busan står i gæld til dens modstandsdygtige flygtninge.
Busan hat seinen zähen Flüchtlingen viel zu verdanken.
Có được Busan ngày nay là nhờ công lao của lớp người tị nạn kiên cường.
Pusan har mycket att tacka sina motståndskraftiga krigsflyktingar för.
Busan debe mucho a sus fuertes refugiados.
Busan está en deuda con sus tenaces refugiados.
Busan owes much to it’s resilient refugees.
Busan deve molto alla perseveranza dei suoi rifugiati.
Busan berhutang banyak kepada para pengungsi yang tangguh.
プサンには 当時の人々の知恵が根付き
難民的韌性，是讓釜山持續前進的動力
堅毅不屈的難民對釜山貢獻良多
ผู้ลี้ภัยมากมายนำความรู้แปลกใหม่มาให้กับปูซาน
Busan devem muito aos refugiados.
Pusan doit beaucoup à la résilience de ses réfugiés.
Busan doit beaucoup à la résilience de ses réfugiés.
Busan saa kiittää sisukkaita pakolaisiaan paljosta.
전후 어려운 환경 속에서 탄생한 음식은 지금은 많은 사랑을 받는 훌륭한 요리가 되었으며
Gerechten die zijn ontstaan in de moeilijke na-oorlogse tijd zijn geperfectioneerd tot culinaire meesterwerken.
Retter som oppstod under trange kår etter krigen har blitt videreutviklet til kulinariske mesterverk.
Retter opfundet efter krigens strabadser er blevet udviklet til kulinariske mesterværker.
Gerichte, die aus der Not der Nachkriegszeit heraus entstanden, wurden zu kulinarischen Meisterwerken perfektioniert.
Những món ăn bắt nguồn từ khốn khó thời hậu chiến dần hoàn thiện thành kiệt tác ẩm thực.
De maträtter som uppfanns under efterkrigsårens svårigheter har fulländats till kulinariska mästerverk.
Los platillos que surgieron de las dificultades de la posguerra han sido perfeccionados en obras maestras culinarias.
Los platos surgidos de las penurias de la posguerra se han perfeccionado hasta ser joyas culinarias.
Dishes born of post-war hardship have been perfected into culinary masterpieces.
Piatti che sono nati nelle difficoltà del dopoguerra si sono trasformati in capolavori culinari.
Makanan yang terlahir pascaperang telah disempurnakan menjadi mahakarya kuliner.
戦後の困難から生まれた料理は プサンの名物料理です
戰後匱乏的年代所衍生的菜餚 已演進成令人垂涎的美饌
戰後窮困日子中的食物不少 已演變成今日韓式名菜
หลังสงคราม เกิดเมนูอาหารใหม่ๆ ขึ้น และได้ดัดแปลงมาเป็นอาหารจานเด็ดในปัจจุบัน
Pratos criados nos difíceis tempos pós-guerra se tornaram especialidades gastronômicas.
Les mets nés des épreuves de l’après-guerre ont été élevés au rang de chefs-d’œuvre culinaires.
Des rudesses de l'après-guerre sont nés des chefs-d'œuvre gastronomiques.
Sodan jälkeinen niukkuus synnytti monia ruokia, joista on sittemmin tullut suuria herkkuja.
피난민 부부가 미군이 버리고 간 잡지를 주워다 팔던 골목길은
Een steegje waar een vluchtelingenkoppel tijdschriften verkocht die waren weggedaan door Amerikaanse soldaten,
En bakgate hvor et flyktningpar solgte magasiner som hadde blitt kastet av amerikanske soldater,
En smøge, som dengang var et sted, hvor flygtningepar solgte magasiner, der blev frasorteret af amerikanske soldater,
Aus einer Gasse, in der Flüchtlinge Zeitschriften verkauften, die amerikanische Soldaten wegwarfen,
Hẻm nhỏ ngày xưa có cặp vợ chồng tị nạn bán tạp chí mà lính Mỹ vứt bỏ
En gränd där ett par brukade sälja tidningar som amerikanska soldater kastat bort,
Un callejón donde una pareja de refugiados vendía revistas que desechaban los soldados americanos
La callejuela donde una pareja vendía revistas dejadas por los soldados americanos
An alleyway where a refugee couple sold magazines discarded by American GIs
Un vicolo in cui una coppia di rifugiati vendeva i giornali scartati dai soldati americani
Gang di mana pasangan pengungsi menjual majalah dibuang oleh GI Amerika
ある夫婦が 米兵の捨てた雑誌を 売っていた路地は
狹窄的巷弄，當年曾有難民夫妻在此擺攤 販賣美國大兵丟棄的雜誌
一對夫婦在一條窄巷專賣 被美國大兵丟棄的舊雜誌
ตรอกเล็กๆ ที่คู่รักลี้ภัยเคยขายนิตยสาร ที่ถูกละทิ้งจากทหารอเมริกัน
Uma travessa onde um refugiado vendia revistas descartadas por soldados americanos
La ruelle où un couple de réfugiés vendait des magazines jetés par les soldats américains
Une allée où un couple de réfugiés vendait des magazines abandonnés par les GI américains
Kujalla, jolla pakolaispariskunta myi amerikkalaisten sotilaiden hylkäämiä lehtiä,
서점가로 바뀌었죠.
is uitgegroeid tot een hele straat vol met boekenwinkels.
vokste til en hel gate full av bokhandlere.
står i dag som en gade fuld af diverse boghandlere.
wurde eine ganze Straße voller Buchhandlungen.
giờ đã thành con phố ngập tràn tiệm sách.
växte fram till att bli en gata fullspäckad med bokaffärer.
se convirtió en una calle entera de librerías.
se ha convertido en una calle de librerías.
grew into an entire street of bookshops.
si è trasformato in un’intera via piena di librerie.
berkembang menjadi toko buku di sepanjang jalan.
書店街に姿を変えました
已發展為書香氣息濃厚的書店街
現在這巷子已成為了書店街
วันนี้กลายเป็นถนนที่เต็มไปด้วยร้านหนังสือ
virou uma rua cheia de livrarias.
est maintenant peuplée de librairies.
est maintenant jalonnée de librairies.
on nykyään lukuisia kirjakauppoja.
그리고 새로운 정착민들이 기본 세간살이를 물물교환하던 자그마한 좌판들은
En een paar bescheiden kraampjes waar de nieuwkomers om de basisbenodigdheden handelden
Og noen få enkle boder hvor de nyankomne omsatte det aller mest nødvendige,
Og et par daværende boder, hvor ydmyge tilflyttere forhandlede basale varer,
Und aus einigen ärmlichen Ständen, wo die Neuankömmlinge mit Waren des täglichen Bedarfs handelten,
Và mấy quầy hàng hiu hắt thuở trước mà dân mới đến kinh doanh hàng tiêu dùng thường ngày
Och ett fåtal anspråkslösa kiosker där nykomlingar utbytte nödvändiga livsmedel,
Y unos pocos puestos humildes donde los recién llegados intercambiaban lo básico de la vida
Y los humildes puestos donde los recién llegados intercambiaban productos básicos
And a few humble stalls where the newcomers traded life’s basics
Alcune delle semplici bancarelle dove i nuovi arrivati vendevano beni di prima necessità
Dan beberapa toko sederhana di mana para pendatang baru menjual kebutuhan dasar hidup
人々が日用品を交換し合った 粗末な露店は
初來乍到的新移民，當年為販賣生活用品 所擺開的簡陋攤位
當年幾個初來的難民 專買日用品的小攤檔
จากร้านขายของเล็กๆ ที่ผู้อพยพ ใช้ซื้อขายแลกเปลี่ยนสินค้า
E estandes humildes onde os recém-chegados trocavam itens básicos
Et les étals chétifs où les nouveaux venus vendaient quelques biens essentiels
Et les quelques étals où les nouveaux venus échangeaient des produits de base
Pakolaisten vaatimattomista, elintarvikkeita myyvistä kojuista
사람들의 발길이 끊이지 않는 우리나라 최대 규모의 전통 시장으로 성장하여
groeiden uit tot de grootste en populairste traditionele markt van Korea,
er nå et av Koreas største og høyest elskede tradisjonelle markeder,
er nu et af Koreas største og mest attraktive traditionelle markeder,
ist einer der größten und beliebtesten traditionellen Märkte Koreas geworden,
nay ghi tên mình trong những khu chợ truyền thống lớn nhất, được yêu thích nhất Hàn Quốc,
är nu för tiden en av Koreas största och mest populära traditionsenliga marknader.
es ahora uno de los más grandes y queridos mercados tradicionales de Corea,
es ahora uno de los mercados tradicionales más grandes y apreciados de Corea,
is now one of Korea’s biggest and best-loved traditional markets,
sono cresciute fino a diventare uno dei mercati coreani tradizionali più grandi e popolari
kini menjadi salah satu pasar tradisional terbesar dan terfavorit di Korea,
今や韓国屈指の誰もが愛する 豊富な品ぞろえが多くを魅了する
現在已成為韓國規模最大且最受歡迎的 傳統市場
如今已變成韓國最大、最受追捧 的傳統市場之一
วันนี้กลายเป็นตลาดเก่าแก่ที่ใหญ่ที่สุด และเป็นที่นิยมที่สุดของเกาหลี
virou um dos maiores e mais tradicionais mercados da Coreia,
ont laissé place à l’un des plus importants marchés traditionnels de Corée.
sont maintenant l'un des marchés les plus grands et prisés de Corée,
on tullut yksi Korean suurimmista ja suosituimmista perinteisistä markkinoista,
김치부터 운동화까지 없는 게 없는 곳이 되었어요.
waar alles, van kimchi tot sneakers, wordt verkocht.
hvor det selges alt fra Kimchi til joggesko.
hvor du finder alt fra Kimchi til kondisko.
auf dem es von Kimchi bis Turnschuhen alles gibt.
bán từ Kimchi đến giày sneaker.
Här säljs allt från kimchi till gymnastikskor.
que vende de todo, desde Kimchi hasta tenis.
donde se vende desde kimchi hasta zapatillas.
selling everything from Kimchi to sneakers.
dove troverete di tutto, dal kimchi alle sneaker.
menjual semua dari Kimchi hingga sepatu.
伝統市場になりました
從泡菜到運動鞋，什麼都買得到
售賣各類貨品包括泡菜以至運動鞋
ขายทุกอย่างตั้งแต่กิมจิไปจนถึงรองเท้าผ้าใบ
vendendo de Kimchi a calçados.
On y trouve tout, des kimchis aux espadrilles.
qui propose tout, du kimchi aux baskets.
jossa myydään kaikkea kimchistä lenkkareihin.
도시 변두리의 가파르고 척박한 언덕에 수백 채의 가주택이
Eerst vulden de vluchtelingen de stadsdelen aan de haven
Busans flyktninger fylte først havneområdene,
Busans flygtninge strømmede først til havneområderne, før de byggede hundredvis af midlertidige huse
Die Flüchtlinge siedelten sich zunächst rund um den Hafen an.
Dân tị nạn đến Busan lúc đầu tập trung ở các khu vực ven bến cảng,
Pusans krigsflyktingar byggde först ut hamnsidans områden med bostäder,
Los refugiados de Busan primero llenaron la zona del puerto,
Los refugiados de Busan vivieron en las zonas del puerto
Busan’s refugees first filled the portside areas,
I rifugiati di Busan agli inizi popolarono la zona del porto,
Pengungsi Busan adalah warga pertama yang tinggal di area tepi pelabuhan,
当時 生活を追われ プサンに逃れた人々が 港にあふれていました
釜山的難民最早居住在 港口一帶
釜山難民最初在港口區 周圍聚居
ในยุคแรก ผู้ลี้ภัยเลือกอาศัย ใกล้กับท่าเรือ
Os refugiados ocuparam primeiro a a região portuária
Les réfugiés se sont d’abord établis près du port.
D'abord installés près du port, les réfugiés de Busan
Busanin pakolaiset asettuivat aluksi sataman lähelle
들어서기도 전에 처음으로 항구 지역에 모여들었던 사람도 바로 이 피난민들이었습니다.
en daarna bouwden ze honderden geïmproviseerde huizen op de steile, kale heuvels om de stad.
før de bygget hundrevis av provisoriske boliger på de bratte, ufruktbare åsene rundt byen.
på de ufrugtbare bakker omkring selve byen.
Später entstanden Hunderte provisorische Häuser an den Hängen der unwirtlichen Hausberge.
sau đó mới dựng xây hàng trăm ngôi nhà tạm trên những đồi dốc cằn cỗi quanh thành phố.
och därefter hundratals provisoriska hem på de branta och karga höjderna runtom staden.
antes de construir cientos de casas improvisadas en las empinadas y vacías colinas alrededor de la ciudad.
antes de construir cientos de casas improvisadas en las empinadas colinas que rodean la ciudad.
before building hundreds of makeshift homes on the steep barren hills around the city.
ma poi costruirono centinaia di case di fortuna ai piedi delle colline che circondano la città.
sebelum membangun ratusan rumah darurat di bukit-bukit yang curam di sekitar kota.
それからプサンの険しい丘に バラックが建ち並びました
後來陸續在市區四面陡峭荒涼的山坡上 興建了數百棟臨時居所
然後在城周圍禿山的斜坡上 築起簡陋的房子居住
จากนั้นขยับขยายมาสร้างบ้านเรือน บนเนินเขาสูงชันรอบๆ เมือง
e, depois, passaram a construir casas simples nas colinas íngremes ao redor da cidade.
Ils ont ensuite construit des centaines d’abris de fortune sur les collines abruptes et arides entourant la ville.
ont construit des habitats précaires sur les collines abruptes entourant la ville.
ja rakensivat sitten satoja tilapäiskoteja kaupunkia ympäröiville kukkuloille.
쉬지 않고 열심히 일한 세월이 흐른 지금, 감천동 주민들은
Na jaren keihard te hebben gewerkt,
Etter å ha arbeidet som helter i årevis,
Efter flere års hårdt arbejde er indbyggerne i Gamcheon
Nach Jahren harter und entbehrungsreicher Arbeit haben die Einwohner von Gamcheon
Sau bao năm bán mặt cho đất, bán lưng cho trời,
Efter många år av hårt arbete och flit
Después de años de trabajar arduamente,
Tras años de trabajo dejándose la piel,
After years of keeping their noses to the grindstone,
Dopo tanti anni di duro lavoro,
Setelah bertahun-tahun bekerja dengan gerinda,
人々がコツコツと働いて 汗水を流したこの地に時が流れ
歷經多年努力不懈 與整建後
經過多年胼手胝足的 生活後
หลังผ่านยุคที่ต้องกรำงานอย่างหนักมาแล้ว ในที่สุด
Os moradores de Gamcheon decoraram e coloriram
Durant des années, ils ont besogné dans leur coin
Après des années consacrées au travail,
Keskityttyään vuosikausia lähinnä työntekoon
창의적인 면모를 살려 길가와 벽면을
hebben de inwoners van Gamcheon hun creatieve kant omarmd.
har innbyggerne i Gamcheon omfavnet sine kreative sider
begyndt at udfolde deres kreative side og udsmykker gader og mure
ihre kreative Seite entdeckt und dekorieren ihre Straßen und Wände mit
dân làng Gamcheon cũng dành tâm sức sáng tạo.
har Gamcheons lokalbefolkning blivit ett med sin kreativa sida.
los residentes de Gamcheon usaron su creatividad
los residentes de Gamcheon han dado rienda suelta a su creatividad
the residents of Gamcheon have embraced their creative side,
gli abitanti di Gamcheon hanno dato sfogo al loro lato creativo,
penduduk Gamcheon telah menunjukkan sisi kreatif mereka,
甘川村の人々が 創造性を開花させました
甘川洞的居民決定發揮他們的 藝術創造力
甘川的居民發揮他們 極具創意的一面
ชาวเมืองคัมชอนได้กลายมาเป็น เมืองแห่งศิลปะ
as travessas e as paredes da região com muita arte,
jusqu’à ce que les résidents de Gamcheon découvrent leur créativité
les habitants de Gamcheon ont exprimé leur créativité
Gamcheonin asukkaat ovat paljastaneet luovan puolensa
예술 작품으로 장식하여
Ze hebben hun straten en muren versierd met kunstwerken
ved å utsmykke gatene og veggene sine med kunst,
med kunst, som har forvandlet kvarteret
farbenfrohen Kunstwerken, die das Viertel
Họ trang trí đường hẻm và tường bao bằng nghệ thuật,
De dekorerar sina gator och husväggar med konstverk
para adornar sus callejones y muros con obras de arte
y adornan las calles y paredes con obras de arte
adorning their laneways and walls with artworks
decorando le strade e i muri del quartiere con opere d’arte
menghiasi jalanan dan tembok mereka dengan karya seni
小道や壁はアートで彩られ
用藝術作品裝飾當地的巷道和牆壁
用各式手工藝品裝飾小巷和牆
กำแพงและท้องถนนเต็มไปด้วยงานศิลป์
transformando o bairro
et décorent leurs allées et leurs murs d’œuvres
en décorant allées et murs d'œuvres
koristellen katunsa ja seinänsä taideteoksilla.
자신들의 마을을 부산 최고의 관광 명소로 탈바꿈시켰죠.
die deze buurt hebben getransformeerd tot een van de grootste bezienswaardigheden van de stad.
noe som har forvandlet nabolaget deres til en av byens mest populære turistattraksjoner.
og er i dag en af byens mest populære seværdigheder blandt turister.
zu einer der beliebtesten Touristenattraktionen von Busan machen.
biến ngôi làng thân thương thành điểm du lịch hàng đầu thành phố.
som har förvandlat området till en av stadens största sevärdheter.
y transformar esta área en una de las principales atracciones turísticas de la ciudad.
que han transformado el barrio en una de las principales atracciones de la ciudad.
which have transformed their neighbourhood into one of the city’s top tourist attractions.
e trasformando così la zona in una delle più belle attrazioni cittadine.
yang telah mengubah lingkungan mereka menjadi salah satu objek wisata kota yang populer.
このエリア全体は今や知らない人はいない 注目スポットになりました
讓社區搖身一變，成為 釜山人氣數一數二的觀光景點
使他們的小區搖身一變 成為城中最著名遊客區之一
ซึ่งเปลี่ยนชุมชนแห่งนี้ ให้กลายเป็นแหล่งท่องเที่ยวสุดฮิต
em uma das atrações mais visitadas da cidade.
qui ont transformé leur quartier en l’un des principaux sites touristiques de la ville.
qui ont fait du quartier l'une des principales attractions touristiques de la ville.
Naapurustosta onkin tullut yksi kaupungin suosituimmista nähtävyyksistä.
감천문화마을은 부산의 톡톡 튀는 개성 만점 문화와
De transformatie van Gamcheon staat symbool voor de nieuwe creatieve,
Gamcheons forvandling symboliserer Busans nyvinnende kreative,
Gamcheons makeover symboliserer Busans kreative, kulturelle
Gamcheons Imagewechsel symbolisiert die neu entdeckte kreative, kulturelle
Sự đổi thay của Gamcheon tượng trưng cho sức sáng tạo, bản sắc văn hóa
Gamcheons förvandling symboliserar Pusans nyfunna, kreativa
El cambio de imagen de Gamcheon simboliza la nueva energía creativa,
La renovación de Gamcheon simboliza la reciente ola creativa,
Gamcheon’s makeover symbolises Busan’s new-found creative,
Il nuovo stile di Gamcheon è un simbolo della nuova energia creativa,
Perubahan Gamcheon menjadi simbol energi kreatif,
甘川 のリノベーション精神は プサンの街中にあふれる
甘川洞的成功改造，象徵著釜山 全新滋生的創意、文化
甘川的蛻變象徵釜山 新爆發的創意
การเปลี่ยนแปลงของคัมชอนสะท้อนให้เห็น พลังของวัฒนธรรม
Essas mudanças em Gamcheon simbolizam a força criativa,
La métamorphose de Gamcheon symbolise le regain d’énergie créative,
La transformation de Gamcheon symbolise l'énergie créative,
Uudistunut Gamcheon symboloi Busanin uutta luovaa,
경제적으로 활기찬 장소를 대표하고 있으며 이러한 기운은 이제 도시 전역으로 퍼져 나가고 있어요.
culturele en ondernemende sfeer die overal in de stad is gaan bloeien.
kulturelle og oppfinnsomme energi som har blomstret over hele byen.
og nyskabende talenter, som blomstrer over hele byen.
und unternehmerische Energie, die in ganz Busan zu spüren ist.
và tiềm năng kinh tế mới khai phá đã đơm hoa kết trái khắp Busan.
och kulturella entreprenörsanda, som har blommat upp över hela staden.
cultural y empresarial de Busan que ha florecido por toda la ciudad.
cultural y emprendedora de Busan, que ha florecido por toda la ciudad.
cultural and entrepreneurial energy which has blossomed all over the city.
culturale e imprenditoriale che è esplosa in tutta la città.
budaya, dan wisausaha Busan yang telah berkembang pesat di seluruh kota.
クリエイティブで未知なることに挑む エネルギーを象徴しています
與創業動能，這些能量 也在整個城市蓬勃發展並開花結果
文化和企業的精神和活力 這些都在城中到處展現
และพลังความสร้างสรรค์ ที่ผุดขึ้นทั่วทั้งเมือง
cultural e empreendedora de Busan que tomou conta da cidade.
culturelle et entrepreneuriale qui a gagné l’ensemble de la ville.
culturelle et économique nouvelle qui a pris possession de la ville.
kulttuurista ja yritteliästä puolta, joka on vallannut koko kaupungin.
세계 최고 수준의 박물관과
Bewonder deze sfeer in zijn uitstekende musea,
Nyt fruktene av den kreative energien i museer,
Du kan se disse kreative værker i verdensklasse på museer,
Diese Energie können Sie sehen:
Sắc màu ấy rực rỡ trong những bảo tàng tầm cỡ thế giới,
Upplev denna energi på museer av världsklass,
Encontrarás esta energía en sus museos,
Podrás ver esta energía en los geniales museos,
See this energy in its world-class museums,
Potrete percepirla nei suoi musei di fama mondiale...
Saksikan energi ini di museum,
こうした熱意が世界に誇る博物館
若想親眼見證，這裡有世界級的博物館
來親睹這活力所在 – 世界級博物館
ค้นหาพลังที่ว่านี้ได้ที่พิพิธภัณฑ์
Isso pode ser vistos nos incríveis museus,
Voyez-en les manifestations dans ses musées, galeries
Cette énergie se ressent dans les musées,
Tämän uuden puolen voi nähdä museoissa,
미술관,
… galeries,
gallerier
...i gallerier
in den erstklassigen Museen,
...phòng triển lãm
...gallerier,
galerías
…galleries,
...nelle sue gallerie d’arte...
…galeri,
ギャラリー
…畫廊
藝術廊
แกลเลอรี
galerias
et festivals
…les galeries
gallerioissa
축제에서 그 진가를 확인해 보세요.
… en festivals.
og festivaler i verdensklasse.
...og på festivaller.
Galerien und Festivals.
...và bao lễ hội.
...och festivaler.
y festivales.
y festivales de la ciudad.
…and festivals.
...e nei suoi festival.
…dan festival kelas dunia.
フェスティバルへと形を変えて街の一部を成しています
…和藝術季
各式節日
และเทศกาลระดับโลก
e festivais.
de calibre mondial.
…et les festivals.
ja festivaaleissa.
번화한 쇼핑 거리와
Je hoort het in het vrolijke bruisen van de winkelstraten
Hør den i den muntre travelheten i handlegatene
Oplev den glade stemning i shoppinggaderne
Sie können sie hören im fröhlichen Trubel
Thanh âm ấy vọng vang trong cái náo nhiệt vui tươi khắp những phố mua sắm
Hör ljudet av den på de livliga shoppinggatorna
La escucharás en el alegre bullicio de sus calles comerciales
Oírla en el alegre trajín de las calles comerciales
Hear it, in the happy bustle of its shopping streets,
Ascoltatela nell'allegro viavai delle vie dello shopping
Dengarkan, di tengah kesibukan jalanan pusat perbelanjaan,
ショッピングストリートや
走在熱鬧的購物街
用耳朵聽這活力所在 — 購物街上的熱鬧歡笑
สัมผัสความบรรยากาศคึกคักที่ถนนช้อปปิ้งสายหลัก
Faça compras nas movimentadas ruas de compras
Écoutez-la dans la frénésie joyeuse des rues commerciales
Elle s'entend dans le tumulte des rues commerçantes
Sen voi kuulla ostoskatujen iloisessa hyörinässä
27만m²의 규모를 자랑하는 세계 최대 백화점을 둘러보세요.
en door de ruim 275 duizend vierkante meter van het grootste warenhuis ter wereld.
og i de nesten 280 000 kvadratmeterne til verdens største varemagasin.
og på tværs af det store indkøbscenter, som er mere end 200.000 kvm stort.
der Einkaufsstraßen und im größten Shoppingcenter der Welt.
và trên diện tích 3 triệu foot vuông của cửa hàng bách hóa lớn nhất thế giới.
och inuti en av världens största varuhus på nästan 280 000 m2.
y en los 280,000 metros cuadrados de la tienda departamental más grande del mundo.
y en los casi trescientos mil metros cuadrados del mayor centro comercial del mundo.
and across the three-million-square-feet of the world’s largest department store.
e negli oltre 270.000 metri quadrati del centro commerciale più grande del mondo.
dan di mal terbesar di dunia dengan luas tiga juta kaki persegi.
世界的な規模を誇るデパートは いつでも熱気にあふれています
和佔地三百萬平方英呎、全球最大的百貨公司裡 遊客的歡聲笑語不絕於耳
佔地三百萬平方呎 全球最大的百貨公司
หรือห้างสรรพสินค้าที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในโลก ที่มีขนาดถึง 3 ล้านตารางฟุต
e na maior loja de departamentos do mundo, com quase 300 mil m².
et en parcourant le plus grand magasin au monde de deux cent quatre-vingt mille mètres carrés.
et dans les 3 millions de mètres carrés du plus grand magasin au monde.
sekä noin 28 hehtaarin kokoisessa maailman suurimmassa tavaratalossa.
그리고 전 세계 미식가와 해산물 마니아들을 유혹하는 음식 냄새와 맛을 느껴보세요.
Ruik het, proef het, in een keuken die fijnproevers en visliefhebbers van over de hele wereld lokt.
Lukt den og smak den i et kjøkken som elskes av foodies og sjømatelskere fra hele verden.
Nyd duften, og smag på det i et køkken, som lokker foodies og folk, som elsker alt godt fra havet, til fra hele verden.
Riechen und schmecken Sie die Energie in der koreanischen Küche, die weltweit begeistert.
Hương vị ấy đậm đà trong những món ăn chinh phục tín đồ ẩm thực và dân nghiền hải sản bốn phương.
Känn dofterna och smaka på maträtterna som lockar hit matälskare och skaldjurskonnässörer från världens alla hörn.
La olerás y probarás en una cocina que atrae a amantes de la comida y de los mariscos de todo el mundo.
Olerla y probarla en una cocina que seduce a gourmets y amantes del marisco de todas partes.
Smell it; Taste it, in a cuisine which lures foodies and seafood lovers from all over the globe.
Sentitene il profumo e il sapore in una cucina amata dai buongustai di tutto il mondo.
Cium; Cicipi makanan yang menarik pecinta makanan dan pecinta hidangan laut dari seluruh dunia.
世界中の美食家をうならせる料理は 五感を使って味わってこそ
品嚐吸引全球饕客和海鮮控的殊滋異味 在直衝腦門的香氣間品味在地的活力
用您的嗅覺和味覺去接觸這活力 欣賞吸引全球食家和海鮮愛好者的韓式烹調
จากนั้นไปลิ้มรสชาติที่ดึงดูด นักชิมและผู้ที่หลงรักอาหารทะเลจากทั่วโลกให้มาเยือน
Experimente a culinária local, que atrai apreciadores de frutos do mar do mundo todo.
Sentez et goûtez-la dans des mets qui séduiront tous les gourmets et les amateurs de fruits de mer.
Elle se goûte dans une gastronomie savoureuse à base de fruits de mer réputée dans le monde entier.
Sen voi haistaa ja maistaa ihanissa ruoissa, jotka houkuttelevat herkuttelijoita ympäri maailmaa.
환하게 빛나는 거리의 분위기를 느껴보세요.
En voel hoe het licht elke avond losbarst in de stad,
Og føl den når byen glitrer i lys hver kveld,
Og oplev det, idet byen stråler hver nat,
Und spüren Sie sie, wenn Busan nachts
Và xúc cảm ấy chạm vào tim ta khi thành phố lên đèn,
Och njut av atmosfären på kvällen när stadsljusen kastar sitt sken
Y la sentirás cuando la ciudad se ilumina todas las noches,
Y sentirla al llenarse la ciudad de luz por las noches,
And feel it, as the city erupts in light each night,
Osservatela ogni notte quando la città brilla di luci,
Dan rasakan, saat kota bermandikan cahaya setiap malamnya,
光の洪水あふれる夜景も圧巻です
入夜後，整座城市燈光燦然
感受這活力之城每晚在夜燈中爆發的魅力
แล้วไปชมแสงสีของเมืองในทุกๆ ค่ำคืน
E, à noite, admire as luzes da cidade
Et vivez-la le soir venu, quand la ville s’illumine
Elle se ressent dans les lumières de la ville la nuit,
Sen voi myös tuntea Busanin upeissa iltavaloissa,
매년 열리는 등불축제의 등불과도 같이 매일 밤 부산의 밤은 빛이 납니다.
net als tijdens het jaarlijkse lantaarnfeest.
akkurat som under den årlige Lanternefesten i byen.
ligesom fra lanterne fra dens årlige festival.
in unendlich vielen Lichtern erstrahlt, genauso wie beim jährlichen Laternenfest.
rạng rỡ tựa như lễ hội đèn lồng hàng năm.
över staden, precis som vid ljusshowen på den årliga lyktfestivalen.
así como con su festival anual de linternas.
como en las exhibiciones del festival anual de faroles.
just like the displays of its annual lantern festival.
come accade durante l’annuale festival delle lanterne.
seperti apa yang ditampilkan di festival lampion tahunan.
年に一度のランタン フェスティバルも開催される プサンを訪れてみませんか
就像燈會一樣金碧輝煌，讓人感受 無以名狀的魅力
例如每年燈籠節的迷人 情調
นอกจากนี้ยังมีเทศกาลโคมไฟ ที่จัดขึ้นทุกๆ ปี
e o festival anual de lanternas.
à l’image des atours de son festival de lanternes annuel.
comme lors du festival annuel des lanternes.
varsinkin jokavuotisen lyhtyfestivaalin aikana.
수 세기에 걸쳐 침입자들을 막아내고 수십 년의 고난과 투쟁의 세월을 이겨낸 부산은
Na jarenlang de vijand buiten de deur te hebben gehouden en decennia van tegenspoed en keihard zwoegen,
Etter århundrer med å stenge fiendene ute, og tiår med trange kår og hart arbeid,
Efter århundreder, hvor man har forsøgt at holde fjender væk, og årtier med trængsler og hårdt arbejde
Nach jahrhundertelanger Abschottung vor Feinden und Jahrzehnten harter Arbeit und Entbehrungen
Sau bao thế kỷ ngoan cường cầm chân kẻ thù và bao thập kỷ nếm mật nằm gai,
Efter att ha hållit fienderna borta från sina portar under århundraden och genomlidit årtionden av svårigheter
Después de siglos de mantener a los enemigos alejados de sus puertas, y décadas de dificultades y trabajo,
Tras siglos manteniendo alejados a los enemigos de sus puertas y décadas de dificultades y pesar,
After centuries of keeping enemies from its gates, and decades of hardship and toil,
Dopo secoli passati a tener lontani i nemici e dopo decenni di fatiche e avversità,
Setelah berabad-abad menjauhkan musuhnya dari Gerbang kotanya, dan berpuluh tahun dari kesulitan dan kerja keras,
長きにわたる外敵との戦い 困難や苦労の果てに
歷經幾個世紀外敵入侵的紛擾 以及數十載的困苦和磨難
經歷過數世紀抵禦敵人入侵 幾十年來的窮困艱辛
หลังจากการปกป้องดินแดนมาเป็นเวลาหลายศตวรรษ การตรากตรำทำงานหนักมาหลายสิบปี
Após séculos batalhando contra inimigos e muitas dificuldades,
Après des siècles passés à repousser l’ennemi et des décennies de privations et de labeurs,
Après avoir passé des siècles à repousser ses ennemis, et des décennies de rudesses,
Lukuisten sotien ja valloitusyritysten sekä vastoinkäymisten jälkeen
마침내 부산만의 독특한 정체성을 가진 도시로 거듭나게 되었습니다.
kan deze uitgelaten havenstad eindelijk zichzelf zijn.
har denne lystige havnebyen blitt noe helt særegent.
er denne by endelig blevet helt sin egen.
hat die lebendige Hafenstadt nun endlich zu sich selbst gefunden.
thành phố cảng mạnh mẽ cuối cùng cũng tỏa hào quang riêng.
och slit, har denna sprudlande hamnstad äntligen fått sin egen prägel.
esta alegre ciudad portuaria por fin ha llegado a su apogeo.
esta alegre ciudad portuaria por fin se muestra como es.
this rollicking port town has at last come into its own.
questa allegra città portuale ha infine trovato la sua dimensione.
kota pelabuhan yang ramai ini akhirnya menjadi mandiri.
このにぎやかな港町はついに 本来の姿を取り戻しました
這個活力十足的港口城終於展現 屬於自己的價值
這個活潑的港口城鎮今天終於 展現自己的風采
ในที่สุด เมืองท่าแห่งนี้ก็ได้เป็นเมือง ที่มีเอกเทศ
esta cidade portuária cresceu e se desenvolveu.
cette ville portuaire amusante s’est enfin épanouie pleinement.
cette ville portuaire rayonne enfin.
tämä vallaton kaupunki on viimein alkanut kukoistaa.
오늘날 부산은 과거와 미래를 서로 연결하여 아주 새로운 오늘을 만들어주는 완벽한 다리가 되어주고 있어요.
Het Busan van nu is een brug, die het verleden en de toekomst in een erg speciaal heden verbindt.
I dag er Busan en bro som knytter fortiden og fremtiden sammen til noe helt spesielt.
I dag er Busan en bro, som forbinder fortiden og fremtiden sammen i nutiden.
Heute ist Busan eine Brücke, die die Vergangenheit und die Zukunft zu einem ganz besonderen Jetzt verbindet.
Busan của hôm nay là nhịp cầu nối liền quá khứ và tương lai với hiện tại đẹp đẽ vô ngần.
Idag är Pusan en bro som perfekt förbinder det förflutna med framtiden.
La actual ciudad de Busan es un puente que conecta perfectamente el pasado y el futuro en un presente muy especial.
Hoy Busan es un puente que conecta a la perfección el pasado y el futuro en un presente de lo más especial.
Today’s Busan is a bridge, perfectly connecting the past and future into a very special now.
Busan oggi è un ponte, che collega passato e futuro in un presente molto speciale.
Kini Busan adalah jembatan, yang menghubungkan dengan sempurna masa lalu dan masa depan menjadi masa kini yang spesial.
プサンは 「過去」と「未来」を格別な「今」へとつなぐ 架け橋としての役割を担っているのです
今天的釜山，有如完美連結過去和未來的橋樑 在現代國際中大放異彩
今天的釜山是一條橋樑，把過去和 未來連結成為獨特的當下
ปูซานในวันนี้คือสะพานที่เชื่อมต่อระหว่างอดีต และปัจจุบันที่แสนงดงาม
Busan é hoje uma ponte que conecta o passado e o futuro com o presente.
La Pusan d’aujourd’hui relie passé et avenir en un présent très particulier.
Aujourd'hui, Busan est un pont qui relie passé et futur, en un présent unique.
Nykypäivän Busanissa menneisyys ja tulevaisuus yhdistyvät saumattomasti toisiinsa.
오감은 물론 영혼까지 만족시키는 부산으로 여행을 떠나 보세요.
Welkom in Busan, een feest voor de zintuigen en de ziel.
Velkommen til Busan, en fest for alle sansene og for sjelen.
Velkommen til Busan – en fest for alle sanser og for sjælen.
Willkommen in Busan – einem Fest für alle Sinne und für die Seele.
Hãy đến với Busan, bữa đại tiệc cho mọi giác quan và cho cả tâm hồn.
Välkommen till Pusan, en fest för alla sinnen och för själen.
Bienvenido a Busan, una fiesta para todos los sentidos y para el alma.
Te damos la bienvenida a Busan, un festival para los sentidos y el alma.
Welcome to Busan, a feast for all the senses, and the soul.
Benvenuti a Busan, un vera festa per i sensi e per lo spirito.
Selamat datang di Busan, pesta untuk semua indera, dan jiwa.
心と身体で味わい尽くす プサンへようこそ
歡迎來到釜山，來一趟振奮五感與靈魂的 完美饗宴
歡迎來到釜山，參加這個感官以及 靈魂的盛宴
ยินดีต้อนรับสู่ปูซาน ดินแดนที่พร้อมอ้าแขนรับ ทุกจิตวิญญาณ
Bem-vindo a Busan, um refúgio para o corpo e a mente.
Bienvenue à Pusan, un festin pour les cinq sens et pour l’âme.
Bienvenue à Busan, une ville qui émerveille les sens et l'âme.
Tervetuloa Busaniin, joka on nautinto sekä aisteille että sielulle.